♪Who were those people♪
♪Who won their love?♪
♪When obsecrating for rosebuds♪
♪I was presented with a garland of thorns...♪
♪Who were those people♪
♪Who won their love?♪
What are you doing?
Did you see his speed?
Then play accordingly!
Umpire Sir!
It's my family!
Hello --
Misbah hit two sixes?
The wretch who couldn't hit a six on a hundred balls scored two sixes on two balls?
Don't worry. India will win this.
Raise the stakes.
I'm losing 7,000 elsewhere.
Alright, I'll pay you 7,000.
Bugger!
One minute!
Hey... Make it 8,000, will you?
It'll save you two and earn me one.
I'm facing a loss somewhere else.
No way!
Come here! Here!
No, back -- go back -- there
Alright, I'll pay you 8,500.
But you're paying me 5,000 if we lose this.
He's off the team after this.
The bugger blackmails on the crease!
Saw that?
Looks like we've lost it, Captain!
Shut up!
Saw that?
Go and get 10,000 from Babur.
The match closes with the next ball.
We've won, Captain!
No, it's that wretch who's won.
We're just getting 1,500 bucks.
God is the greatest...
Farah!
Here she comes.
Peace be upon you.
-God protect you from the evil eye. God be praised.
You don't know how long he's been gloomy.
Look at him gladden at the very sight of you!
I'll -- be back.
Please don't leave without fixing the date.
Let your father come.
I'll say it plainly:
I'll have dinner only when you've fixed the date.
And you better say something too.
Last time, you remained quiet, and Dad said he'd think.
No... He's not a dosser.
He just couldn't get a job after doing his BA.
He spends some time with the lads.
One of them must be a loafer.
That's got him a bad name, too.
You know the Reverend only too well.
He calls him a sinner if he isn't back before dusk.
Don't talk about Beenish.
She'd clearly told me on Eid -
'I accept, Aunt, but he does not'.
Uh -- no, Kulsoom --
Why won't he?
He must be teasing her -- just for fun.
No, no, no -- Kulsoom, he's 25, not 28.
In fact, he's 25 just because the Reverend wrote it a year older to get him admitted to school.
Here.
24,000.
That makes for a total of
98,000.
Where do you get so much money from?
What do you mean?
I work hard; I earn it.
You're lying.
If you also think I'm lying, Dad's going to rush to the police station with his rants about religious values!
He'll get me booked!
You're into gambling, aren't you?
What?
As if that's even possible!
Reverend Subhanallah's son is into gambling?
You're not a sister.
You're a sworn enemy.
What if Dad found out?
It's just a matter of two days.
I'll deposit it in a bank once I open an account.
Alright, I'll keep it.
But please
Tell me about your job someday.
Doubting me again?
No.
All I want is that if Dad gives his judgement on this matter, I can say firmly,
'This is my brother's hard-earned money'.
Don't talk about him.
He even thinks it's unlawful to deposit money at a bank.
Keep it inside, quick.
Mum will start on it if she saw it.
This is your room.
Have a look and let me know if you need anything.
But I stayed in the room upstairs last time...
This is the best room in the house.
As the date is fixed, you rise in status.
But...
But what?
You don't like it?
The room's alright, but...
I would often glimpse her from the room upstairs.
Shall I arrange a meeting?
Is it possible?
She's said it herself this time
Before Dad comes back, you are invited to meet her on the terrace.
When does he come back?
Ask when you're invited!
-When?
9 o'clock sharp.
Dad comes back at 10.
You've got 40 minutes.
Mind if I share a few precautional musings about the meeting?
Please.
Talk from afar.
And don't talk about your many cars and châteaux.
Talk about your deep love!
Of course...
If she asks something, give a thoughtful answer.
Sure.
And even if she comes close, don't place your hand on her shoulder or hand!
I won't, but please tell me - she accepts this espousal, right?
Did you see her cheeks redden at the sight of you?
Redden --?
-I did!
It means she's very happy.
But when I tried to talk to her,
She had a go at me -- so to speak.
You were a stranger then.
You were just the son of a friend of Dad's.
Dad's got many friends, and they've got many sons.
She doesn't talk to all of them.
Now I get it...
When the date is decided,
Gently place your hand on hers.
I'm sure she won't push you away then!
Did you say it?
Yes.
What did he say?
He said he wouldn't place his hand on your shoulder or hand.
What?
Did he intend to?
No.
I just forbade him as a precaution.
Mum says nothing's written when it comes to the intentions of men.
Who knows - he might have reached for your hand the moment you started talking.
That's why I warned him.
Alright.
I've told him to meet you at 9 o'clock.
I'd said 9.30.
Dad said he'd be back at 10.
What if he got back at 9.30?
Fine.
Alright then.
Why do you want to meet him though?
Is there any good reason?
It may help me someday.
I'll tell you everything once I'm done,
And I pray that everything will help you someday!
Alright. I'll be with Mum and Aunt. Go up as soon as the clock strikes 9.
Okay?
Ahh... Let my past remain ensepulchred beneath dust.
For my past is but obloquy to me.
Splendid!
-Great!
Reified by yearning, meed for my endeavours...
Is nothing but inglorious woe?
Do not chronicle my love before me;
Let me show the fortitude of my love.
Excellent!
-Well said!
And that ebrious gaze that abandoned me -
I was never one to admire it;
The very tresses, gaze, cheeks, and form,
I can find elsewhere if so I desire;
Excellent!
-Great!
The lilies destined to blossom for them
Can blossom far from the reach of their gaze.
Lovely!
-That's great!
Very well said!
-That's the real deal!
Now you're talking like a man!
Forget the harpy and marry someone better!
Rent a house in front of hers.
Show her you're a man!
I bet, she'll file for divorce within moments!
Called her again, did you?
Got scolded again?
No mate...
She hung up at the sound of my voice,
Then answered when I tried again,
And said, 'Who is it'?
I said, 'I'm Sajid'.
And she said, 'Sajid who'?
Do you get it?
It means skive off, chap.
'Leave me alone'!
That's it.
One of these days I'll curse you.
I'll say, 'May you be accursed with such adoration'!
It scares me the way you keep on laughing to yourself.
Why?
I mean --
She writes to you twice a week, right?
What if she forgot one week?
As if that's possible!
She's not like your sweet Chanda;
She'd die without me.
Do you know what she's written this time?
You got her letter?
Oh, yeah... Today's Saturday, after all!
Read it out to us.
Hearing her words...
It feels as if one Chanda might've killed all affection, but another Chanda might just resurrect it.
Her name isn't Chanda!
So tell us her name today.
I have great respect for her.
I'll mention her honourably.
Some other day...
Hear her letter first.
Man was born for his compassion towards the suffering;
For there was no shortage of beings for subservience alone.
There was no shortage of divine spirits and angels to serve God.
Why was man born?
Man was born for the pains he goes through, for his deeds of compassion,
Which is why the rights of servants --
Oh --
O Lord, I beg You to grant me the best of Your favours.
May you have a long life, son.
'Dear Afzal',
She always opens with 'Dear Afzal'!
Shut up! Go on, mate.
'How are you?'
'All well?'
'I see the best in you whenever I see you.'
'Always fresh!'
Where do you meet?
Mum's the word!
Go on. Don't stop for his questions!
'You stay with me for but a few minutes,'
'Eager every second of it to leave.'
'I still wait for the day you will be before my eyes all night,'
'And I, like a devotee, shall relish every moment of my deity's presence...'
'When will it be, Afzal? And how?'
'Seeing you vivifies me,'
'And the grim reaper seizes me the moment you leave.'
'I'd die without you.'
That's it?
That's it.
For my sake, at least tell me her name.
I won't tell you that!
You and your 'I won't tell'.
Mehtab?
Yes?
Let's sit down, shall we?
Where should I sit?
Why, right here, with me.
If you want to ask something
Or say something, please do.
All I want to say --
You're very beautiful.
That's it?
Uh -- No...
When you softly called out, 'Mehtab',
I swear I nearly died at that moment.
Your voice is fatal.
Fatal?
Uh -- I mean it -- in a sweet manner...
It touches my heart.
Where in Karachi do you live?
Block 2, Clifton.
Wow...
Your house must be quite the chateau.
Ye -- No.
It's small.
How many cars do you own?
Just -- just the one parked here.
As in... You're going through hard times?
No -- It's not like that.
Nothing like 'hard times' in my life.
Then why aren't you telling me?
You've got five cars.
You own four houses -
Two in Karachi, and two in Larkana.
The thing is -- Lubna had warned against talking about houses and cars.
You'd be angry.
Monseigneur's here.
Peace be upon you, Dad.
And upon you, peace.
Aunt Shugufta and Mehtab are here.
Oh?
Aunt said she'd leave only after the date is decided.
Alright, I'll fix it today.
But tell me - she's happy, isn't she?
I think so...
I want to study further.
Why not?
Even after I'm married.
I'm doing my Master's in Economics,
And I'll go to London for my MPhil.
Why?
What do you mean?
What's wrong?
And most importantly,
I want to get a job that's as glorious as it is grandiose!
My wife will work?
No way!
Everyone will insult me.
Who?
Friends -- relatives -- all of them...
And in all honesty, you'd hardly have the time.
You'll have to take care of me.
I'm so childlike.
I'll need you all the time.
So -- won't you work?
I don't need to work.
I've got some 200 million in my account already.
I've lost track of how much I spend every year,
But the balance just refuses to come down.
You know why?
Why?
I get 20 million from just the land revenues.
So what'll we do after our marriage?
Have a jolly good time, of course!
What happened?
Was it something I said?
You know, when I was young --
Leave my hand!
I despise people like you
Who are in this world just to 'have a jolly good time'.
Everything was fine until now.
Then she started talking about her education.
She said she'd go to London for her MPhil after our marriage.
Stupid, innit?
I mean, London's best for honeymoon!
Lu -- Lubna!
What time is it?
It's 10.
Call Sofia
And tell her the match is not fit.
What do you mean?
It means that Reverend Subhanallah won't allow
The wife to be cared for on money earned through gambling.
Gambling?
He's won 24,500 today,
And 16,000 of it in the match that Pakistan had lost.
Good Heavens!
I've heard he even smokes weed when he gets the chance.
And... Some girl writes him letters.
I don't know who she is,
But, sitting with his friends,
He reads her lettes out to them.
You're starting to question yourself, aren't you?
So am I...
When I teach the kids these days,
It feels as if
They're staring at me,
Sniggering... 'Look at your own son',
'And look at what you talk about'.
Even the prayers lack that spirit.
Every moment, a fear stings at me as I step out of the Mosque...
That the police
May be at the doorstep holding that scoundrel by his collar.
Tell him to leave this place!
For the righteous and the sinful cannot live together.
Is it only an accusation,
Or do you have proof of it as well?
I'm not accepting it without evidence.
I come with reliable information.
One of these days, you were struck with calamity at 'information'.
You'd even told me not to repeat it unless proven true.
Present evidence if you have any,
Else in this matter of crime and punishment, your word cannot be taken for the truth.
And if you have evidence,
I swear by you
I would hit him with my shoes a hundred times.
I'll order him to leave this place myself,
For the righteous and the sinful cannot live together.
I don't accept it!
Tell Dad I'm not marrying Mehtab Chawla.
You should've said this earlier.
Now they've gathered to decide the date.
It's not the end of the world!
Go and whisper into his ears; tell him --
-- That I don't accept it.
He'll get up instantly.
You're strange.
You were enjoying the feast!
What happened when you swallowed what you bit?
I just can't swallow this one!
Can't do anything now.
For my sake,
Tell Mum. I'll handle the rest.
Alright, I'll tell her.
Please.
What if he died when he heard it?
There's a possibility he might...
Go!
Don't lie to me.
You won 8,000 in the local match, and 16,000 when Pakistan lost.
What?
I swea --
Yes, I swear.
You're lying again.
Dad knows everything.
He mentioned everything and said that the righteous and the sinful cannot live together.
Does Mum believe it?
Don't talk about her; I believe it!
I also know that the 98,000 you kept with me - You won it all in gambling!
And who's this girl who writes letters to you?
Girl?
Did you say it?
Yes.
How'd it go? Who did you talk to?
Mum.
Great! Then?
I know.
Mum would've said it flatly -
'Leave it, Ibrahim, she doesn't accept it'.
Isn't it?
It isn't.
Mum stuffed this sweet into my mouth the moment she heard it.
Gave me this plate of sweets, and said, 'Give it to her'.
The 15th of December is the big day.
Who is it?
It's me, Afzal.
Had your dinner?
Yes.
Go and sleep then.
Peace be upon you.
And upon you, peace.
May you live long.
Is anyone coming, or will you go on your own?
Who would come? I'll go myself.
Did he come?
Yes.
I figured as much.
I'll go and rouse him.
He can drop you.
Leave it be.
Shame on he who calls himself a believer,
And drops another at the Mosque and leaves.
Tell him when he wakes up,
I'd like to meet him before noon.
And remember, if you're listening,
Today's meeting will be more important than your conventicles!
I love someone else.
What?
Did you hear that?
He'll be struck by lightning to hear this.
I hear
He's staying here to celebrate.
And if he's staying,
I'll meet him again tonight.
What do you intend to do?
What does it look like?
With two teardrops, I'll say,
'I'm sorry, Mehtab',
'But it's important that you know the truth before our marriage'.
'Before our marriage'?
'It'd hurt you far more if someone else told you later on'.
Honestly, what is it?
'I love someone else'.
'Truly'.
'I've loved him since our schooldays'.
'We used to write letters to each other',
'But now, we talk over the phone for hours'.
'We'd sworn oaths',
'Made promises',
'To live and die together'.
'But what good is it now'...
'Now that I'm getting married off to you'...
'I have to be yours'.
A fib.
-Might as well be!
But he will believe it.
He'd die for real this time!
He won't.
He'd much rather kill his dreams,
And say as he leaves,
'No way I'm marrying her'!
Great.
Were it so easy...
Will Dad stay quiet?
Will he hurl abuses at them?
-No.
He'll ask Mehtab's Mum why he was rejected.
And she will ask him, 'What happened so suddenly'?
'You've changed after a second meeting'.
Don't worry.
He'll change.
Halt!
What are you doing?
Oh! It's you, Reverend.
Peace be upon you.
And upon you, peace.
This man 'ere's a thief.
Stole a mobile and tried to make a run for it.
Round him up and get him in the car.
You're going to the Mosque?
Yes.
Shall I drop you?
No --
I'll go on my own. Please, do your duty.
With peace.
Have some tea
Or you'll catch a cold.
Thanks.
Dad's left?
Yes.
Why are you following me?
Just a second.
You're into gambling, aren't you?
You give me all your winnings, right?
[Call to prayer]
These pennies will, one day, become serpents and scorpions.
They sting Dad today; they might as well sting you tomorrow.
Leave it be.
It's my hard-earned money.
You smoke weed.
A lie!
God forgive!
Alright, give me the keys to your cupboard.
What's in the cupboard?
Her letters
That you read out to your friends.
The unholy trinity of your sins...
Dad knows everything.
You should be ashamed of yourself, Afzal.
She writes you letters, and you read them out to your friends?
Like a pallbearer of her honour!
Take this tea back,
And leave.
Don't accuse me like Dad.
Swear that it's all false.
Who's she?
I won't tell you her name.
I've sworn to her.
And what about Beenish?
Beenish?
Aunt Sofia's daughter?
What's up with her now?
Mum's decided to get you married to her.
Blimey --
She's coming here in a few days.
Beenish too?
Perhaps.
Let them come.
Let her come too?
I'll give her the reply she needs.
She won't even turn to look at me again.
As if she was going to, anyhow.
No need to give her a 'reply'.
Shatter her dreams quietly.
Don't slam it into the ground, roaring,
'I've shattered them'!
Why not just say no to her?
Tell her
That she's only got wanton rampage waiting for her.
Anyway, who's she?
Don't tell me her name, just where she's from.
Not far away.
In fact, this city itself.
She must be beautiful.
Very.
Fairy-like.
She's happy with you?
Why not?
I'm sure she knows that you
Smoke weed, gamble,
And read out her letters to friends?
There!
You're my sister for just a few moments,
Until Dad starts speaking from your mouth.
You, too, should remember, Afzal,
You're Reverend Subhanallah's son.
Go to sleep early.
Dad wants to see you before noon.
Translation: Aditya Misra © Prime TV