♪Who were those people♪
♪Who won their love?♪
♪When obsecrating for rosebuds♪
♪I was presented with a garland of thorns...♪
♪Who were those people♪
♪Who won their love?♪
You're my sister for just a few moments,
Until Dad starts speaking from your mouth.
You, too, should remember, Afzal,
You're Reverend Subhanallah's son.
Go to sleep early.
Dad wants to see you before noon.
And don't you dare raise your voice.
Better stay quiet than lie.
He's even worried that you may have to suffer for your lies.
Take the cup.
What are you doing?
I won't let go.
What's the big deal now?
Can't I hold your hand?
Let go!
I'm getting angry!
I don't fear your fury.
And I never will after 15th December.
Let go! What if someone saw --
So what?
They'll just think of it as our expression of love.
No, it's not that.
Let's meet tonight?
Tonight?
Hush! The walls have ears!
On the terrace?
Yes.
Let go now!
When?
9 o'clock!
Why not 8?
D -- Dad watches the news at 9.
Oh...
Promise?
Tell me.
You'll be there, won't you?
Oh,
I'd be there at 8.30.
Ohhh...
When will the night fall,
And when will it finally be 9...
Come here.
I was listening tales of her childhood shenanigans.
God forgive.
She used to hold the dog by his ears!
Hey!
I never knew there were such dogs --
I mean --
The kind that'd let you hold them by the ear?
She's talking about puppies.
Oh.
Thank you.
Mum, we're not leaving this evening.
Why?
I've got to meet someone at 9.
Here in Hydarabad? Who?
One of my friends, Mum -- You know...
It's okay if he has plans.
You can leave tomorrow morning.
Yes Mum, we'll leave tomorrow.
Is she still asleep?
No, she's just a bit coy.
Hold it right there.
Do you know
He's told everyone about the meeting tonight.
What?
Yes.
Said before Dad he's got to meet someone tonight at 9.
The blighter!
Don't call him a blighter like that.
He didn't tell the who!
I'm calling him a blighter because
He grabbed my hand in the morning
And refused to let go.
Stop laughing.
I felt I should hold the meeting right at that moment,
Bring him to the terrace and drop the bombshell on him.
Please don't do that.
Break hearts, sure, but elegantly.
Piece by piece,
Slowly,
One subtle blow,
Then another.
By the way,
Science hasn't verified something like 'broken hearts'.
For now, let's just say it can shatter like glass!
I'll verify your claim scientifically!
Sweet Jesus!
At first, he looked like a real gentleman.
Now, he seems neither gentle nor a man!
Mind your anger until 9 p.m.
Or Mum will think you're about to wage a war!
Peace be upon you.
-And upon you too.
Don't bring me to the market, Reverend...
He'll find out.
I swear, he'll kill me.
Do not fear anyone if you're doing the right thing.
I'm right here.
I won't let anyone touch you.
And upon you, peace.
So what do I have to do?
Come with me to him.
And say without fear what he's done.
Before him?
To his face.
And
Those letters you used to listen to
Do you remember
Any of what she used to write?
Most of the times, just...
'I'll die without you'.
God forgive!
Where does she live?
In this city, apparently.
Because he only has her letters.
No envelopes.
So she lives nearby...
Yes...
May I go now, Reverend?
Didn't I tell you to go to him,
And present every piece of evidence?
No, Reverend.
If I saw him -- I'd deny everything -- I'd swear --
That I never said anything!
God curses the liars!
Where are you off to now?
If you believe what I said, okay --
Or just think I lied to you...
He doesn't gamble,
Doesn't smoke weed --
There's no letters --
Hey --
Listen to me!
The boorish --
And upon you, peace.
May you live long.
I can guess about the local matches.
But who told him about the India-Pakistan match?
And -- to the devil with the matches!
He even knows about the letters!
How can it be?
MUst've been Sir Timmy!
He knows everything.
He didn't name my friends,
But he mentioned everything.
'Reads out her letters to his friends'!
You're doubting me?
You're talking about doubt?
My friendship is at stake.
Eladio!
Don't talk about Eladio.
The lad's a selfless servant.
You're accusing him because he's poor?
Must've been Sajid.
No --
Why would he?
Alright, I'll talk later.
Dad's here.
The meeting's about to start.
Peace be upon you.
And upon you, peace.
Talk as a father.
Not a Reverend.
Call him.
Call him here.
Would you like some water?
I said call him here.
He's coming in a few minutes. He's afraid.
Strange.
He's fearing me
And I him...
Tell him to come.
I've come without evidence.
I'll talk differently.
Peace be upon you, Dad.
And upon you, peace.
Come.
Sit.
You may leave.
Shut the door.
Arifa says you were fearing me.
Happy to hear.
Why were you fearing me?
It's nothing like that.
Yesterday, you mentioned gambling --
Weed --
I was ashamed of myself.
I was afraid
About what I'd say to you...
You forgot the one about her letters...
Anyway.
That chapter has closed by itself.
I found no evidence of any of it.
The poor devil who'd informed me
Didn't agree to testify.
The poor soul ran away, frightened of you.
You're henceforth acquitted of all three accusations.
So rejoice.
You're - God be praised - acquitted
I've got to answer for my crimes.
My Mum's no more,
Else I would've been acquitted too.
What have you done, Dad?
I'm guilty of
Raising my dear child by rightful means.
There's another crime.
You've achieved renown in the neighbourhood,
And I'm helpless before you.
And thus I've decided to spend the rest of my days
In the seclusion of the Mosque.
No Dad...
Not in seclusion.
You'll stay at home.
I cannot stay here.
Why not?
Because you're here.
And because of you, I fear what fate awaits me.
Ruqaiyya!
Stop leaning against the door and come inside.
Listen to me.
Bless you.
I have failed to find evidence against your son.
I am ashamed of myself
And therefore leaving this house for the seclusion of the Mosque.
Pack the essentials and give me leave.
What are you talking about, Reverend?
Didn't you say,
'Talk as a father'?
Now bear witness,
That I talked as a father.
I'm exiling the Reverend to the seclusion of the Mosque.
Go!
Fall at his feet!
Apologise with your head at his feet!
Dad!
Forgive me for all my sins!
For God's sake, forgive me!
Right.
First, offer your noon prayers.
We'll talk later.
See?
He hasn't forgiven you completely.
But he will.
Purify yourself
And stand in the foremost rank.
That's what he's hinted at!
Go!
It's you!
Headed for the Mosque?
Yes.
When did this happen?
Today.
Dad said, offer your prayers, or else --
Or else?
I -- I'm getting late.
You're out on the streets,
Don't laugh like that.
That bloke...
He's a ruffian.
No --
He's gone to pray.
Don't turn to look back.
It isn't proper!
Blimey, Aunt!
He's my best friend's brother.
Reverend Subhanallah's son.
You don't know,
But Eladio tells me everything.
He's with those yobs,
Gambling --
And who knows what else!
Alright,
But he's going to pray now.
Peace and Mercy of God upon you.
There is no God but the Almighty.
Hear me, O Lord...
I begin in the name of God, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful.
You are Peace, and from You is Peace.
Amen!
Give us our lives in Your surrender, and admit into the Safety of Your Peace.
You are the Most Praised, the Most Sublime.
The Lord of Majesty and Bounty.
And blessings of God be upon Mohammad and his companions.
And hit him so hard,
He gets cold feet the moment he sees her!
she must've hit him on the feet!
Come in.
Are the dresses ready, or will they be tomorrow?
What are you doing? Get your hands off!
What was that?
Just kidding.
Get used to it. After our marriage...
Why did you come in my room?
You said, 'Come in'.
Oh God.
Get out.
Out!
This isn't right.
You get angry every now and then.
And I --
I've been waiting for 9 p.m. since the morning.
Nothing can change our plan for 9 p.m.
I swear.
I won't be a minute late.
I was getting bored alone
And thought if a little meeting before the night --
Hey!
Splendid!
Nothing so splendid.
I'm leaving.
Chap sneaked into the room.
I thought it was you.
Anyway.
Are the dresses ready or will they be 'tomorrow'?
Not tomorrow, the day after.
He said he was cutting vegetables with his wife when he cut his hand.
Splendid!
What?
Nothing.
I said nothing.
Come.
Here.
Dad --
Why have you brought me here?
I swear that thing about the letters is false.
I swear by you!
Who said anything about any letters?
I've talked to Monseigneur.
Saw him praying and told him about you.
When he heard you'd done a BA, he said, 'Bring him to me'.
'I'll give him a job'.
Come. Come here.
Come here.
Tell me, how big is your heart?
See for yourself.
The fact is,
I'm afraid.
Afraid of being dishonoured...
We're the kind who'd die for honour.
The times have changed.
People compromise on honour a little.
Perhaps.
But why are we talking about it?
Let's talk about something else.
Right --
What did I start on --
I think we have an understanding.
Should I say it?
What?
Please don't be disturbed to hear it.
I won't. Promise.
It's bad.
But best told.
If such things come out in the open after the marriage,
Even lovers get divorced.
God forgive!
Place your hand over your heart.
Do it!
The thing is
I love someone else, Mehtab.
Since childhood...
He was a classmate.
We used to write letters everyday,
And now, we talk for hours over the phone.
He'd say, 'I'll die without you'.
And
Before the date was fixed, I'd say the same.
But now, I guess
I have to sacrifice my first love for Dad's sake.
You must be feeling very bad,
But --
-No.
I don't feel bad at all.
I'm chuffed to see
That you didn't conceal your past like other girls.
You've got courage.
Said it all to my face!
I swear by you,
I admire you even more now.
I'm proud of you.
Everything about honour aside,
Your past is none of my concern.
Was this the compromise you were talking about?
Hey -- Wait -- Wha -- Ruined the sleeve there!
Look, Mum! My sharp dressed brother!
God bless!
Ward the evil eye off him!
Do I look good?
Sightly, I swear!
It's 'as God has willed'!
Ward the evil eye off him.
Do anything you want; many eyes will be fixed on him today!
Look at him, Dad!
I am looking.
This is how gentlemen look. Just perfect!
Right. Turn away.
Don't stay before my eyes too long like this.
Have him walk under the Holy Qur'an when he leaves.
It's his first day at the office.
And
The bloke looks sightly indeed!
Don't look back if a sweetheart looks at you.
These looks could kill!
The Lord is happy with me,
Or perhaps
With you, Ruqaiyya.
To be honest, Dad
He is happy with me.
I'd prayed with tears in my eyes that noon.
Like this.
With my hands folded
Saying,
'If the meeting does not bring good news, I'll be found making up for missed prayers'.
God forgive you!
Threatened God?
How's this a threat?
Is it a threat if I'm angry with you and say I won't eat?
It's a threat when I don't do something for you.
Which I do without failure.
Yours, and His.
Alright, don't list your favours.
And don't reason in ignorance.
And you just have a jolly time standing.
Pack him some egg bread for lunch.
Okay.
He'll be there until five!
Come.
Go.
Keep the bag in the car.
Hey!
Where are you going?
You said she's not coming to see me off.
Obviously.
How can she come to see you off with Dad standing there?
That's why I was going upstairs.
She might be crying.
What?
It's just that
Goodbyes
Can be fatal for lovers.
And this restriction on seeing me off!
How she must be feeling!
Aunt's in the car and Mum and Dad are waiting for you.
What's she doing?
Anyway.
I needn't ask that...
She must be distressed.
Don't look up.
Dad often finds excuses to check.
Sorry, but
It's 2013 and he's stuck in 1913.
But anyway,
Tell her it'll be this way after our marriage too.
Will she trouble herself weeping and wailing like this?
I may even have to go somewhere for a week or so.
I'll tell her.
And tell her it's just four months until December.
Here I go,
And there comes December.
If the Lord wills...
Alright.
One more thing.
A secret.
Tell her
Not to call the wrong people.
What do you mean?
I can't tell you the whole thing.
Just tell her indirectly
To let bygones be bygones.
Stop!
Wait.
Yes.
Now, begin in the name of God,
Bow your head, and walk on.
Wait a second!
You left your lunch box here.
Dad!
He said the tie and the lunch box didn't match well enough.
Won't leave a good impression.
One who submits to God
Leaves an impression with his humility, my dear.
He's humble, Reverend.
He's doing his duty.
Will he be humble only if he has his lunch box?
Go, my child.
In the name of God.
Go.
O Lord, the Most Exalted.
Oh!
I was so overjoyed I forgot to ask you... What's his rank?
And how much will he earn?
He's a clerk,
And he'll earn 10,000.
That's it?
You made him a clerk...
With a third division all the way from matric [GCSEs] to BA,
Monseigneur has been generous enough
To not ask about his experience,
Else I would've said,
He's a proper gambler.
And he, too, can see through a man so well
As to have him in the accounts department!
God is great indeed!
If the noon prayer had its effect,
He will prosper,
Or else it'll be another albatross around my neck.
My neck
And his tie make quite the combination!
It's only four months until December.
They shall pass.
My foot!
Don't trouble yourself weeping and wailing.
What?
Farah Mehtab sounds so good!
And you sound so bad!
You can have it in writing.
The December shall never come
When Farah Ibrahim will get married to Mehtab Chawla.
Or so it can be said that 2013 will end with 11 months.
For the first time, there will be no December in a year!
Bye!
Hey, Afzal!
Complete with trews, shirt and a tie!
Who decked you up?
What do you mean?
I deck myself up.
You're going on a date!
I'm going to office.
Office?
You know Sheikh Ibrahim Cotton Mills?
I'm the Accounts Officer.
Monseigneur Ibrahim?
Forget him.
I'm an officer!
What a spunky lassie he's got --
Who are you talking about?
Don't show your depravity!
Think of people's daughters as your sisters.
Third division in matric [GCSEs],
Third division in inter [A-Levels],
Third division in BA,
And what's your name?
Afzal [The Excellent One] Subhanallah.
Subhanallah Afzal [The Splendid Afzal] suits you better.
Subhanallah is my father's name.
Experience?
Zero.
No third division here, eh?
I haven't started work that would gain me experience.
Why has Monseigneur appointed you?
On my father's recommendation.
Who is your father?
He's a priest at the Mosque.
He leads Monseigneur's prayers.
Oh...
Miss Rosy!
Yes?
Meet Mr Subhanallah Afzal.
Take him to his desk,
And show him how to fill a voucher.
Just filling vouchers?
Teach him whatever he can learn.
Alright.
Come.
Go.
Sit.
Come a bit closer to me.
Yes?
I said come a bit closer, so that I can show you how to fill a voucher.
Alright.
Mr Chengezi was insulting you so bad.
Didn't you feel angry?
A bit.
But you were smiling.
Do you know why?
Why?
One day, I will insult him.
Back to work now.
Who is it?
Lubna!
-How are you?
Come in.
-Take this; come back after an hour.
If it isn't our sweet Lubna!
Peace be upon you, Aunt.
And upon you, peace.
How are you?
How many months has it been?
I've brought sweets for you.
Sweets? Why?
Someone's getting married!
Yes.
-Isn't it?
Getting married?
You're so shameless!
You're telling us when you bring us sweets?
Who's the man?
First, ask who's getting married!
Farah?
Yes.
Thank goodness she's found someone.
Sit down and talk,
I'll get some tea.
First have some sweets,
Then I'll tell you the bitter reality.
I've had sweets, now tell me!
Easy, girl!
Let the sweets sink in!
Let's go inside.
Now, fill this voucher.
Say, Ibrahim Cottons sold cloth worth 1,000,000
And the buyer gave a cheque of 1,000,000.
This white one's the debit voucher.
It's written on it,
But because of the white colour,
It can be seen
Rather easily.
The bank is the debit and sales are the credit.
Now
Fill a debit voucher.
Fill it.
Are you married?
You didn't mention this --
I'm asking you.
Tell me if you're married.
No.
Not yet.
Then, there's a lot more I can teach you.
Don't answer the phone.
Mr Chengezi minds it.
And he can't stand personal calls at all.
What does he do when he can't stand something?
Aye, Babloo?
7 p.m. sharp.
What is it?
A match against the old colony lads.
Floodlight.
Why are you laughing?
I can't play.
Can't play?
What's this guff?
I've put 50,000 on the line.
10,000 for you if we win.
Shut up!
No more matches now.
I've started working now.
I'm on duty.
Want more cash, eh, bugger?
Alright,
15,000 for you.
That okay?
-I won't even agree to 20.
Enough for now. Bye!
It --
Was a friend.
A punter.
Gambles on matches.
That's the last call you answered in this office!
No, sir.
That was the first.
Miss Rosy, tell him!
Tell him how to behave in the office before teaching him how to fill vouchers!
I'd warned you.
Didn't you see him
Crawl back?
The crab.
Translation: Aditya Misra © Prime TV