♪Who were those people♪
♪Who won their love?♪
♪When obsecrating for rosebuds♪
♪I was presented with a garland of thorns...♪
♪Who were those people♪
♪Who won their love?♪
Oh God!
She's suddenly taken to praying!
Be done with it and tell me what's wrong this time!
God knows what she's praying for!
I was praying that this Sunday not fall on the 27th.
Or that the 27th not be a Sunday.
Are you touched in the head?
I'm getting married this Sunday, you blighter!
No you're not.
I've prayed you don't!
You're envying your own sister?
Do you remember
How you said that you're making this marriage happen?
I said I made the engagement happen.
So slow down!
What can be done now?
When Farah thinks of something, her decision is final.
You don't need to think anything.
Your engagement was no engagement!
That was a part of your treatment!
What?
You mean --
That bleeding psychiatrist was treating me?
We were both of the opinion that you'd need a different kind of shock therapy.
You love someone else
And you're not ready to admit it.
And that blighter said with complete confidence,
That the moment it'd come to marrying him,
You'd shriek,
'No way, I can't marry Sibtain'!
So he doesn't love me?
He was conniving!
You don't love him either.
You were conniving too!
You were just getting even with Afzal.
Afzal again?
Who the devil is he?
And whose is he?
The Farah from the letters?
You?
And now that blighter Jasmine --
Well,
Jasmine's my friend now;
I won't call her a blighter...
I was never with him, Farah.
I was lying.
Lying?
I was just putting up a show.
Because of that dolt Sibtain.
The blighter read a bunch of his books
And said, 'If you name Afzal, she'll say with evident agony -'
'"Shut up, Lubna"!'
'"Don't even think about him"!'
Yeah, right...
Remember when I slapped you and said,
'Don't even think about him'!
But you stopped there!
What should've I said?
What you can't bring yourself to say;
What that unfortunate bloke couldn't muster the courage to say.
You've killed each other,
Too reluctant to accept that you love each other.
I've said it a hundred times over and will say it a thousand times more,
I don't love Afzal!
I DON'T LOVE AFZAL!
Sit down.
Here's all the letters
Besides the one in your possession.
They're not letters, Jasmine.
They're an unsung chronicle of love
That ended
When I got engaged to you.
Take this
And torch these with your own hands.
Just think as if
Afzal had a dream since his childhood days;
His dream unfulfilled, he felt too ashamed to even talk about it.
Don't look at me;
I'll never tell you who wrote these letters.
Will you torch these, or should I?
No one will torch them, Afzal.
Letters written in love are not to be burnt.
You kiss and lift them to the eyes,
And hold on to them like a holy book that touches the heart.
You are under my oath, Afzal -
Burn all you want in the flames of her searing remembrance,
But never burn these.
Arifa, I want to meet Farah.
Right now?
Right now.
Have you asked him?
I won't ask him.
I'll tell him when I'm back.
Does she go to bed by 11?
I don't know.
Then call her.
Tell her
I must see her.
And...
What is it exactly that you want?
Nothing, really.
I've got a few questions in my heart.
I just want to satisfy myself.
I'll talk to Lubna.
Hello, Arifa!
How are you?
I don't know.
Hey?
What happened?
To be honest, I'm furious!
I feel like murdering that chuffing Farah!
She's getting married this Sunday.
Why do you need to murder her now?
Don't tell me she's rejected the proposal!
No.
That's exactly why!
She's determined.
Alright; by the way
Jasmine wants to meet her.
Everything alright?
I don't know.
She said that she wants to meet her right now.
Tell her to come over.
But how will she come?
Tell her to get ready.
I'll send a car.
Thank you.
Shut up, mate.
The car will be there in ten minutes.
Okay.
-Bye.
Would you look at that, Ruqaiyya Begum?
He's rubbing my feet to sweeten me up!
Yeah, and I can see how you're not sweetening up!
Let's just say
I can no longer feel that warmth...
There's this knot in my heart now.
Keep at it, dear.
It'll untie this knot.
Do you remember, when I had the heart attack, you said,
'The Reverend has been overcome by the father'?
You were right.
Yeah, you were...
If a Reverend is more fatherly,
He may succumb to a weakness of honour.
Not that I've been dishonoured, really,
But, still,
I am in no position to avouch.
Why are you laughing?
I'm feeling sleepy,
And
I haven't even taken any sleeping pills!
Is everything alright?
Nothing's alright.
There's something new every day!
Where is she?
Sleeping.
She'll wake up today.
Upstairs?
Yes.
Stay here.
Just tell me where her room is.
Go up and turn right. First room on the left's hers.
Open your eyes!
I'm actually here!
I don't believe this.
Is everything alright?
Get up. We need to talk.
I'm up.
What is it?
I've got a few questions, Farah.
Will you answer them?
Ask away.
Do you know Miss Mary?
Miss Mary?
No, I don't know her.
The year was 2007.
Where were you studying back then?
I was doing my O-Levels back then...
Oh, yeah -- Just a minute.
Miss Mary D'Souza was a teacher at my school.
Blimey, was she stern!
She used to get angry a lot; perhaps it's because she was a divorcee...
How did you find out about her?
I don't think even Lubna remembers her name.
You'd mentioned her in a letter to him.
You'd threatened him,
'If you waited in front of the school or tried to look at me, I'll have you caught'.
Who'd I write that to?
Afzal.
I've got the letter in my bag if you want to read it.
I don't need to read it.
I know there's someone who writes him letters.
Her name is Farah.
And I'm getting a bad name because of her.
There's just one way now, Jasmine.
Grab Afzal by the collar and ask him,
'Tell me'
'Who is this Farah'?
Why shouldn't I ask you first?
Why is the name of that Farah's teacher Mary D'Souza?
Perhaps that's why you're marrying a psychiatrist.
You know, deep down, that you're ailing.
If he's not willing to tell me,
You're not willing to admit it either.
You wrote these letters, Farah.
It's possible
That you fell in love with him sometime
And, afflicted with that love, you wrote those letters.
But you realised later on
That he's not your class!
This is why you hide your face in shame,
Lie to everyone,
And tell everyone that it's some other Farah.
You're getting married this Sunday, aren't you?
That's it.
It's just a problem until your marriage.
You'll be cured,
And so will he...
He holds on to your letters even now.
He's forgotten everything else he should've held on to.
Wake up, Farah.
Don't ever sleep in peace
With the knowledge that you've given many others sleepless nights.
Ask the driver to drop me home.
Come.
I've given her such a slosh she'll be left wondering.
What'll she be left wondering?
Just
What this Jasmine is made of!
So,
What are you made of?
I've said it clearly to her,
'You used to write letters to Afzal'.
Why did you say that?
Miss Mary D'Souza
Was a teacher at her school.
Tell me, then,
If it's her teacher who's mentioned,
She's the one who wrote those letters, isn't she?
She's not admitted it yet.
But now, she's within my grasp.
I couldn't dare imagine!
For the love of God,
How much my brother has been humiliated because of those letters!
I'm here now,
And I'll leave only after I've got the truth from her.
Didn't Mum ask you where you had gone?
No... But she was staring at me quietly.
What's this?
Afzal's diary.
He used to write it everyday up to his FA [A-Level] days.
There's another one from after he'd completed his FA [A-Levels].
I've gone through both of them
But found no clue.
May I read this?
Let me see what he used to write.
Go on.
'If love were a cricket match, I would've won'.
'I gambled for the first time today'.
'Won 500 Rupees'.
'I gave them all to Arifa',
'And Arifa is the kind who pulled me up, asking where I got it from'.
'What could I do'?
'I saw her anger and lied to her'.
What's the matter?
Just a second.
Whatever is it in that letter?
She's got wind of who wrote those letters.
And the clue lies in the one she's got in her bag.
Why is she doing this, Ruqaiyya?
Searching and probing like this, she
Will lose something which is hers.
Where is she?
Call her here.
I will talk to her.
Come in, my dear.
She's outside, waiting for you to call her.
What is all of this, my dear?
You're remembering the one
Who should've been forgotten?
And you're reminding him, too?
No way.
Give me that letter.
In fact, bring me the rest of them too.
We'll consider it a sacrificial offering
To mark your engagement when we burn those letters.
Who'll you serve those coconut biscuits?
Who'll you see and say, 'When she comes, it feels as if Afzal has come'?
I do not need such consolations, my dear.
Afzal's here now.
I'm afraid you'll lose him again
If she got married this Sunday.
Did she write those letters?
Yes.
No.
That's completely wrong.
That can't be.
She didn't write those letters -- She --
She was ready to swear on the Holy Qur'an.
She was telling the truth.
She wasn't lying one bit!
She wasn't lying one bit, yes.
But she'll accept it today
That she wrote the letters.
You should accept it too. Please.
The car's here.
Car?
I'm going to meet Farah.
Please, allow me.
You've met her last night too.
You didn't ask for my permission last night.
I thought you'd stop me because it was late.
And I feared that I'd go regardless.
I didn't want to disobey you.
What'll you do today?
I won't allow you today either.
I'll go regardless.
For now, I'm obligated to disrespect this command.
What did she just say, Ruqaiyya?
How respectfully has she said
That she'd disrespect my command!
She's pronounced her judgement as she left, Reverend.
She's decided she won't live under the same roof as Afzal.
What happened?
Who was there in the car?
Jasmine.
Try as much as you like, Jasmine, she won't admit it.
She will, today.
The circumstances and evidence have changed.
She'll be saying to you in a while that she's written the letters.
Where is she?
In her room as usual.
She's suddenly started offering additional prayers.
Go up, turn right, first room on the left, right?
Yes.
Don't come upstairs today.
Seriously.
Don't.
Hold it there!
Offer the rest of your prayers after I've left.
I dropped in again, didn't I?
Sorry, Farah, but I had no option.
I've sworn I'd leave only after having you admit it.
Admit what?
Sit.
Say that you're the Farah who wrote those letters.
I swear by God --
-Don't!
Just say it for someone's sake.
Why should I say it, mate?
Because the Farah who wrote those letters isn't anyone else.
What?
What do you mean?
Alright, remember -
Sometimes,
Sometimes, you saw him outside the school
And sometimes, at the gates of your college.
Yeah, I did...
In fact, I saw him outside the college very often.
Because Arifa used to study there.
He used to come to pick her up.
He came to see you, Farah.
He used to glimpse you, secretly.
You, the daughter of the owner of Ibrahim Cottons,
And he, the son of a poor Reverend.
That is why he never mustered the courage to say anything or talk to you.
So?
And when he felt
That he'd never be able to talk to you,
To tell you that he loves you,
He took the other road to his love.
What?
He started writing letters from you to Afzal.
All that he'd wanted to tell you,
He believed he had,
And all that he wanted to hear from you,
He wrote in his letters which he'd read to his friends.
He believed in his mind
That you loved him,
But also accepted
That you can never be his.
I feel sorry for him...
Yes.
I feel sorry for him too.
He's admitted it?
Obviously,
He would've admitted when he's been caught.
He's been caught, Farah.
But he hasn't admitted it
Because I never asked him to admit it.
That's your fault, then.
He's your fiancé.
You should've grabbed his collar and said,
'Hey Mister'!
'What's going on here'?
As if it started today;
As if it'll end tomorrow...
This will go on until he dies, Farah,
Or love itself dies.
Interesting...
So, now you want
That I forgive him.
No, Farah.
Now, I want that you confess it.
Admit it that you love Afzal
And admit it
That you had written all those letters.
Very funny.
I don't think I'm crazy like you!
Honestly,
Are you actually his fiancée
Or just say it to scare us?
You could say that...
I just say it to scare you.
The blighter had scared me when he first met me.
He said, 'I'll throw you out'!
No!
He didn't throw me out.
Just
Said it for the sake of saying.
He doesn't know how to talk to girls.
He'll learn when he talks to you.
But now that he's been with me for a few days,
He's learnt something.
He said it very politely when he came for the engagement,
'Will you get engaged to me'?
It felt as if --
As if --
He'd cursed me!
Cursed?
Who in the world says, 'Will you get engaged to me'?
If he loved me, he would've said,
'Will you marry me'?
I swear by you,
I would never have thought about who writes him letters!
Whether you're the Farah or someone else,
I would've trampled her underfoot!
He deserved a girl like you
Who'd break others to pieces for his love.
But he only wanted you
Who'd broken him to pieces.
He'd come from Hyderabad a broken man.
One who comes broken from Hyderabad
Cannot be patched in Karachi.
He said to me a day before the engagement, 'Jasmine',
'I don't love you'.
And I'd known he'd say that
Because he never knew any love
Except his love.
So, when he came to talk about the engagement, it felt
Like he'd come to amuse me.
You were getting engaged that day.
He'd come to settle a score.
I, too, thought, 'Get on with the engagement'.
'What's the big deal'?
'The moment he'd turn to look back',
'The engagement would break'.
I'm getting married this Sunday.
It'll all be clear this Sunday.
You'll see,
He'll marry you this Sunday.
He'll settle a score again.
Why, Farah?
Why must only you two play this game of settling scores?
How say I play my move this time?
And when I do, you'll realise,
That one who comes broken from Karachi
Cannot be patched in Hyderabad.
Don't break your engagement!
-Oh, never...
I would never.
But what do I do about him?
When he startles at the sound of your name,
The engagement breaks.
No -- He's nobody to me;
I know he's Arifa's brother,
The Reverend's son,
And now also that he writes letters to himself under my name...
The blighter!
You love this blighter.
No?
You'd die without him.
Very funny.
You look for him when you can't find him around,
And when you look for him, no one else can get him.
Oh -- No, it's nothing like that!
I don't love him!
I don't even think about him!
Y -- You can
Y -- You can have me swear on it!
-Alright.
-Alright. Swear on it.
Swear by God you don't love Afzal.
He's watching you right here,
Show Him;
Tell Him you don't love Afzal.
She's found out that this Farah had written the letters.
How?
How'd she find out?
Miss Mary D'Souza was a teacher at Farah's school.
She mentioned her name in a letter.
The same letter which Jasmine has in her bag.
There's just one way left for you.
Swear to God and say
That you don't love Farah Ibrahim.
You're Reverend Subhanallah's son.
You wouldn't swear a false oath, would you?
Stop.
What about Jasmine?
She'll be coming back after having her admit it for real.
And what if she actually admitted to it?
What about your engagement?
It'll break, won't it?
Won't it?
-She'll never admit it.
She'll swear over it and say she'd not written the letters.
And it is indeed true, Arifa. She didn't write those.
Then Miss Mary D'Souza -- Her handwriting --?
I told you
That's not her handwriting.
Don't you feel ashamed to think
That she loves you, and she's looking
For the one you love?
Come.
Come on, mate.
You started down the path of God. Where'd you end up?
Nowhere.
You just left Hyderabad and ended up in Karachi.
And here you are, thinking whether
You've never left Hyderabad,
Or never returned from Karachi.
How are you, Mr Fiancé?
Come in.
I saw you playing cricket.
You're such an ace, mate!
Don't say 'mate;' Dad may hear it!
Allow me these parting discourtesies, my love;
Who knows what may become of me
Who knows what may become of me and you?
Tell him to not look at me with such fury!
Don't look at her with such fury!
Why did you go there?
Eh?
For the sake of Uncle Reverend's coconut biscuits.
Please agree to what I'm saying!
And for your Mum's sake.
She finds you in Farah.
Translation: Aditya Misra © Prime TV