♪Who were those people♪
♪Who won their love?♪
♪When obsecrating for rosebuds♪
♪I was presented with a garland of thorns...♪
♪Who were those people♪
♪Who won their love?♪
I'm afraid.
Good.
What do you mean?
You're saying it's good that I'm afraid?
Do you know why I'm afraid?
Yes.
You're afraid he's married the Farah from the letters,
And you think he'd come back from Karachi
With two kids.
You're also afraid
That they would recognise you instantly,
And run to embrace their 'Aunt'.
Why would they embrace me?
And how'd they know me?
Farah,
One never forgets
The one who wounds him.
So, your name would be mentioned often
Before Farah and the kids.
There!
You're getting goosebumps, aren't you?
Do you know what that means?
What?
Well,
You know it very well.
You're wishing that you die before seeing that day.
Which day?
C'mon, mate, don't act so innocent.
One gets the chills when one's so perturbed.
God forgive...
However did you even think that
He'd marry the Farah from the letters,
And he'd have two kids who'd - God forbid -
Call you 'Aunt' the moment they see you?
Out!
Think again,
I'd actually leave.
Remember how you'd pleaded with me to get me here?
I'm not my problem; you are!
I'm seeing the psychiatrist in the morning because of you.
Dad's booked an appointment in the evening too.
What happened to him?
I told you...
He thinks his brain's been french fried.
He's fine.
That's just a problem with his English.
You're laughing, aren't you?
Wait,
I may just curse you!
Hey!
I'll say,
'May you be in my condition',
'Stumbling around restlessly',
'Living, but not alive',
'Mortified, but not quite dead'!
Oh...
So that's how you're feeling...
And
YOu never even told me!
I'm telling you now.
Cursing you, too.
Thank you, Farah.
You're thanking me now,
But you'll get your deserts later.
That's what they all say -
'You'll get your deserts when you fall in love'.
But this knave called 'love' never got me!
Who's talking about love?
You're bubbling with love head to toe,
And asking who's talking about love!
By the Lord, lassie,
However do I tell you I don't love him!
I'm even sad
About not marrying Mehtab.
I dragged principles in for no reason,
Otherwise, he was right -
Who goes to London to study after getting married?
Should I call him?
Mehtab?
Of course.
The poor lad would've gotten up.
He'd be shivering right now.
May the Lord keep him happy.
Hey!
Why are you throwing your responsibility onto the Lord?
If you've realised your mistake, just call him.
Marry him, take him to London. Keep him happy.
I'll meet him when I go to Karachi.
Oh...
So you're going to Karachi?
Might as well.
If I understood what Mehtab said,
I'd definitely go to Karachi.
Why are you laughing?
For God's sake, Farah,
You'd follow Afzal to Timbuctoo if he went there.
I mean,
You've started respecting Mehtab for him. Wow...
Lubna!
You better leave.
Oh, please!
You'd be left afraid and alone here if I went away.
I won't be afraid.
Think over it, Farah Ibrahim,
You're taking a risk.
I know very well -
Lost love becomes a ghost
That comes back to haunt you.
Who?
Afzal, of course.
C'mon,
Get out!
Okay, fine.
Close the doors and windows.
Although doors and windows do little to deter ghosts,
It just satisfies one's heart.
Okay?
Good night.
-[Call to the morning prayer]
[Call to the morning prayer]
-Oh, sorry...
-Good morning.
[Call to the morning prayer]
You've kept God busy, Ruqaiyya Begum.
He
Looks after everyone's children.
He will take care of your son, too.
Don't worry.
He'd better.
There's no power but God's!
This 'He'd better' part isn't exactly...
Proper.
You coming between the Lord and me is not proper either, Reverend.
Please be kind enough
As to leave the Lord with His woman,
Beyond the Reverend's control.
Whatever are you saying,
Ruqaiyya Begum?
What could I do, Reverend?
A mother's courage is most unlike that of the Lord.
Nothing that's His ever gets lost,
But mothers' sons do get lost.
That's why I've been chanting requests -
'If You remember Your love for Your Creation',
'Don't ever forget a mother's love for her son'.
-God forgive!
Does He ever forget?
Exactly.
That's what I'm asking.
'Did You forget it when it was my turn'?
Your mother's saying words of disbelief!
There's never disbelief in a mother's words, Dad.
The one who gives birth to children is talking to the One who gave birth to all of Creation.
I'm sure she knows how to talk.
Is it that the two of you leave me speechless now,
Or is it that the one who's left
Has taken my words with him?
But remember, Ruqaiyya Begum,
If there's so much as a speck on the honour of God's men,
Miracles happen.
Listen, Reverend,
Mothers pray for miracles in their helplessness.
It's an obligation on God's men to do something worth showing Him.
Then save your prayers.
Every day, to do something worth showing,
I go to watch cricket.
I spend the entire afternoon there,
At the playground where your Afzal
Used to play matches he'd gamble over.
If I got wind of his whereabouts,
I'd rush to his doorstep that instant.
And...
Don't be so selfish in your sorrow
As to forget the pain of Afzal's father.
Just think
You're tormented in one way,
And I'm tormented in another.
Arifa!
Come and shut the door.
It's time
For the Reverend to do his fatherly duties.
What --
What's up with the people?
Why are they saluting me?
Why are they calling me 'Afzal Bhai'?
-The cowards are so helpless --
The cowards are so helpless --
-Peace be upon you, Afzal Bhai!
How are you, sir? Would you like to have some tea, sir? A cold drink?
-I'm fine.
No, thank you very much.
Okay, sir.
That's how they talk to their oul fella.
Whatever does that mean?
Why are you so tensed? If they salute you, just greet them back.
-But --
Why now? They never used to.
And I didn't quite get this one about the oul fella and 'Bhai'.
Alright, come. I'll tell you.
How are you?
-I'm fine.
Greetings, sir! How are you?
Go on.
Tell me.
What do these sudden salutes mean?
Why were they calling me 'Afzal Bhai'?
Sit.
Cripes, mate...
Be done with this chapter of 'sit', 'stand up', 'I'll tell you at home'.
Just get to the point.
How tall are you?
You're asking about my height?
Just tell me how tall you are; I'll answer your question.
5' 11".
5' 11"...
Weight?
Again?
Tell me your weight.
81 kg.
Now, look around and tell me how many lads
Are above 5' 11"
And 81 kg.
You'd find more than a handful.
They all lived here,
Yet, before you came,
Why did girls have to fear for their honour
Before a 5' 11" hoodlum like yourself?
Because measuring a man's height and weight tells nothing about how much courage he's got.
Hoodlums are not made by their capabilities,
But by the fear and cowardice in the hearts of people.
The one they fear
Becomes a hoodlum.
Tell me about the salutes.
Why were they saluting me?
The people have begun to fear you because they think you're a bigger hoodlum than Wali.
What?
One surprised 'What' isn't going to change the ways of the city.
-Here.
Here's your lunch.
So much?
It's nothing much, really.
Just many dishes.
What've you got?
Potato, meat, chicken ginger, and mixed vegetable.
Why are you looking at each other?
Try it and tell me how it is.
I've cooked the chicken ginger.
Yes, it's good. Good.
You haven't even tasted it!
It sure looks good!
When did you see it?
There's a lid on the top.
I can see it on your face! The chicken ginger sure is delicious!
-There, now!
And what are you doing, looking at me like that?
Just a spot of lipstick's got you stunned!
Well,
That isn't something I could say myself.
Mam's told me not to.
How say you tell me -
How does this lipstick look?
It -- I -- It's good.
So you think you've been sent here as part of a conspiracy against you,
And you're otherwise perfectly normal.
-Of course.
Know what,
I'm the first girl in my family
Who's seeing a psychiatrist for her treatment.
Do you know why?
Why?
Because they think of psychiatrists as shrinks and aliénistes in my family!
Aye?
'Aye' as in?
Is it right?
Naw at all!
So,
You were saying
That Lubna's your younger sister?
Yes.
And who's this Afzal?
Afzal?
I didn't even mention his name.
Hold on!
You've been briefed before I came here.
Naw at all, you've named him five times in twenty minutes.
How could that be?
I shut up even so much as a thought of him.
Why do you think of him?
I mean, who is he to you?
Hold your horses, Monsieur le Docteur!
He's nobody to me!
Lubna's best friend is Arifa,
And he's her brother.
An ace loafer and wastrel.
Just last month
He gambled one last time
And ran away from the city.
Oh!
Where'd he go?
No idea.
But I hear he's gone to Karachi.
I also know why he's gone there.
Why?
Don't you think it's
Something I have nothing to do with?
Aye, right, you don't,
But...
I thought I might as well ask now that you've mentioned it.
He's having an affair with a girl.
He's eloped with her, I'm sure.
Want to know her name?
Yes?
You'd laugh.
Naw,
I promise.
Farah!
That blighter's name is Farah, too!
His parents are very sad...
It pains me to see them.
So, you pay them a visit now and then?
No, Monsieur le Docteur!
It's nothing like that.
I just felt, for once,
That I'm partly to blame for his leaving, too.
So, I went over to comfort them.
Why did you feel so?
I mean, if you shut up so much as a thought of him,
How could you be responsible for his leaving?
Leave it be, Monsieur le Docteur.
It's a long story...
We've got plenty of time; I can listen to long stories.
I think
It's quite personal.
Look,
Nothing's personal when seeing a psychiatrist.
Everything the patient tells is strictly confidential.
'Patient'?
You're calling me your patient?
Uh -- Naw -- It was a slip of the tongue...
I meant,
We call those who consult us for advice our patients.
Oh...
Don't call me a patient again, though, okay?
Sure.
Right.
The story begins
With Mum getting me engaged to one Mehtab.
The lad's a proper bounder.
I agreed to it in the beginning,
But when I interviewed him after the engagement,
I realised
That --
His intentions aren't right!
What were his intentions?
Well,
I won't tell you everything.
Just think
That he had no intention to work even after getting married.
How'd he get his two square meals if he didn't work?
He has no issues with that.
He's got millions lying in the bank,
And he gets his share from that.
But I
Curse a lad like that,
Who'd keep millions in a vault
And make a show of having a jolly good time before the poorer ones!
You don't look like you're among the 'poorer ones'.
What do you mean, Monsieur le Docteur?
My Dad doesn't like wasting money,
But he could buy the likes of Mehtab in a moment.
Okay, okay.
Please, go on.
What happened next
Has brought me before you.
Just think
As if I've made one foolish mistake.
Peace be upon you, Dad.
And upon you, peace. Where are you?
At the psychiatrist's clinic.
So you actually went there!
I couldn't believe it when your Mum told me.
Where is she?
She's with the doctor. It's been an hour.
She was alright, wasn't she?
She was, Dad.
Seeing the patients at the clinic, she said,
'I can't see a single mad man here'.
Tell her to talk to me when she comes back.
Sure.
But...
What?
She isn't going to get cured.
Are you alright?
She went there just casually; otherwise, whatever is wrong with her?
Nothing's wrong with her, Dad.
But she isn't ready to be cured yet.
What's this logic, mate?
Do you know what you're saying?
I'm telling the truth, Dad.
She's come to the psychiatrist because she, too, knows that she's --
-The psychiatrist will help her with her condition.
I've heard he's very intelligent.
He listens to the patient for hours, and solves the problem in moments.
Let's hope for the best.
Okay, Dad,
Bye.
Okay.
There was such a scene
When he brought his family along for the engagement.
And guess what,
They even brought a ring!
His Dad took it out of his pocket and showed it.
And, Monsieur le Docteur, it was the bleeding limit
That my Mum and Dad were chuffed, too!
They didn't even think
How a girl like Farah
Could ever even think about a wastrel like Afzal!
What happened, then?
What could've happened?
As if I'm meek as a lamb,
And I'd go along with him, bleating!
Right at the time of the engagement,
I exposed him!
I shoved the engagement ring in his face.
Right in his face?
No.
As in, refused to get engaged.
I showed him his place.
So, to speak,
'Shoved the ring in his face'.
Aye, figuratively speaking...
Of course...
He'd be hiding his face in shame, then?
No, Monsieur le Docteur.
He left Hyderabad after that.
And honestly?
I did feel sorry that he left.
Why'd you feel sorry?
I mean,
Why'd you feel sorry for such a man?
His family's missing him a lot.
Looking at them,
I torment in pain, too.
That's strange...
He's having a ball in Karachi,
And people are tormented here for him.
Please, Monsieur le Docteur,
Don't say that.
Don't say what?
That he's having a ball in Karachi.
That's not what Dad thinks.
Forget about Daddy, tell me what you think.
The thing is,
If you saw him, you wouldn't really think he's the type.
Gambling's his only vice, really.
He'd even been acquitted in the case with Rosy.
Who's Rosy?
A blighter.
Turned out
She was drooling over him.
Dad ousted her.
Oh...
So she worked for you.
Interesting story,
And a bit funny as well...
Innit?
Alright, tell me,
Are you in the same condition now?
What condition?
Shutting up even so much as a thought of him.
Do you shut it up even now?
No.
If he comes to my mind,
I do think about him...
What, for example, do you think?
That he should come back to Hyderabad now.
It's better that he come here.
Why is it better for you?
I'm not talking about myself, Monsieur le Docteur.
If he stayed before his parents' eyes,
It'd give them peace.
Such noble thoughts...
Hmm... He ought to come back now.
What if he didn't?
He'd have to, Monsieur le Docteur!
Reverend Subhanallah's prayers won't go to waste!
And with his Mum having the Ayat'e Karima [Prayer for Relief from All Difficulties] recited,
How much longer could he keep running away?
Plus, I've vowed to offer 100 additional prayers.
You don't know, Monsieur le Docteur,
My wish gets fulfilled
Just after 12.
At least tell me what the doctor said.
I will,
But promise me
That you'd never go to a psychiatrist
If you had such a problem.
Why? What happened?
These psychiatrists are real wizards,
They even ask things one wouldn't even tell Mum and Dad.
So he asked you everything?
Yes...
And you told everything?
Of course.
Then?
What about your treatment?
Treatment?
So you think I'd gone there to get treated?
Do you know,
He called me a 'patient' by mistake.
Had to apologise for it.
No good then...
No.
He told me not to silence any thought of him.
He said there's nothing wrong about it.
He's got a point...
You can't throw a thought out if you never let it in.
That's why...
Whose thoughts?
Afzal, of course.
So you told him that you think about Afzal?
I don't think about him.
Just the occasional thought...
Blimey...
Is there anything wrong with that?
No.
Nothing wrong with it.
But tell me, what'd you tell Mum and Dad?
What'd I tell them?
Dad called me when I was there.
He asked me to call when leaving the clinic.
Mum's asked thrice, too,
'Why is it taking so long'?
I said, 'The treatment's taking time'.
'Treatment'?
Yes --
I said whatever came to my mind.
But be prepared with your answer.
Think of what you'd say when Mum and Dad would ask.
Would you tell the truth or lie?
What truth do I tell them?
Just say that
You think of Afzal.
I'd never say that!
Yeah, yeah... You never even told me!
By the way, what kind of thoughts do you have?
Romantic, or
The bland desi type [South Asian, rustic, unsophisticated]?
As if I'd romance Afzal!
I know you won't, but who knows about thoughts?
Maybe, someday, in a romantic mood...
Shut up!
Honestly, though, Farah,
It's about time you brought out the sly lass hiding behind your veil of innocence,
And said openly, 'I won't leave anyone in peace until I've found peace myself'.
What do you mean?
You crazy lass,
Why are you toying with yourself?
If you love Afzal, just say that you do.
Nobody will say anything.
For God's sake, Lubna,
I don't love Afzal!
At least think before you say something!
Me with Afzal --
Eww!
Never!
What happened?
Can't you believe it?
Not one bit.
Am I lying?
You're not lying,
But you don't know the truth.
And it pains me to say
That the day you come to know the truth
Would be the day I'd say,
'You're lying'.
In that case, why don't you get this mirror out of here?
Here's your tea.
If my eyes fall on it while passing by, I take a look.
I'll say it straight, Mam,
Who doesn't like a pretty face?
Have your tea.
He's 25-ish, I'm sure.
At this age, a man with a fair face has already found a girl for himself.
What'd you do if he told you that he's found someone?
So what?
As if I bother!
I'd see your bothered self
In this mirror, then.
You wouldn't say, then,
'Get this mirror out, Mam'.
You'd say, 'Destroy this mirror'.
Have your tea.
Give me one, too.
A cigarette?
Yes.
Why?
Just...
Just feel like smoking.
Just get to the point and tell me what's in your heart.
The job as a security guard, you know...
I've agreed to do that.
As in,
We'll go to your friend tomorrow.
I'd apologise to him, and you can talk about the job.
But tell him I won't have my hair cut.
As if you're enlisting in the army! 'Hair cut'! Seriously?
Don't worry; I'll talk to him.
May --
May I sleep?
Sure.
Go to sleep.
She won't come by herself,
You could've climbed up the stairs and asked her.
Well, she'd only lie to me.
Who taught her to lie?
Only girls who conceal their heart's secrets from their mothers
Go to see psychiatrists.
Wow. That's rather well put.
But isn't this an insult to you?
I mean,
Why would the daughter conceal her heart's secrets from her mother?
I think there's a communication gap.
I mean,
She fears
You'd tell me whatever she told you.
Who else could I tell?
Why do you need to tell anyone?
Listen to her, and tell me your decision.
Just the what.
So would you do
As I say?
Of course.
But think over your decision carefully before telling me.
May I compliment you?
Why, right now.
You're the watermelon that's red on the inside.
-Hey!
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
So you're sleeping in my room today?
No?
You aren't afraid, are you?
Not at all?
I'm in no mood to talk.
I'm very sleepy.
You'd have to listen to one thing.
Done.
You'd have to reply, too.
I've always got my reply ready.
Shoot.
Tell me,
What do I have to do to show you
That'd make you believe that I don't love Afzal?
What are your options?
You'd give me the options, right?
If you made me choose between death and him,
I'd rather die.
Blimey!
So much hatred!
I don't hate him.
But I don't love him.
Still don't believe it?
Pray tell,
Don't you have options either?
I've got one.
It'd shock you if you heard it.
You might even kill me right here.
I promise you,
I'll do anything,
But I won't even touch you.
Ready?
Yes.
Say it.
Think again - It may just kill you.
Put a sock in it!
My name's Farah Ibrahim.
I'm made of the same mettle as the mighty boulders.
Allow me, then...
Let me marry Afzal.
Good morning!
Oh!
Good morning.
Your bed tea!
Now for free! For you!
Where's Babu Hamid?
Babu Hamid's
Gone to get some milk and tea.
Isn't this
Too much of a formality?
I'd have to have the second cup now.
I thought I'd have it here.
Because why not? It'd give you company, too.
Right...
Sit.
What's your wife's name?
Wife?
Haven't you gotten married yet?
No.
I get it.
What do you get?
You're having an affair.
Innit?
No, I don't.
Oh, shoot!
You're lying to Jasmine?
You're hiding it from me, right?
I don't lie.
I only lie to those I fear.
So there's someone you fear!
Wow...
Who could that be?
Arifa.
My sister...
Reverend Subhanallah.
My Dad...
And your Mam?
I don't lie to Mum.
I just can't...
What've you come to Karachi for?
No idea.
But why are you asking?
Nothing, really.
Just a pastime.
Do you know how to read palms?
I do.
I can read the love line quickly!
Show me your hand.
No --
I don't believe in these things.
Dad starts saying 'No power but God's' if he sees it.
Such childish talk!
Is Dad around, watching?
The thing is,
I don't like it either.
That, or is it just that you're afraid of getting caught?
There's a line of love on my palm.
It's very long.
But I don't know where it leads.
Just show me the line.
I'll show it the way.
Good joke.
Nice tea.
Thank you.
Mam has fanciful suspicions about you.
Oh?
Like what?
She thinks you're married,
Or you've got a girl after you.
But it isn't quite possible, really...
You're educated,
You look lush, too.
Surely, a couple of lasses would be dying for you.
First time someone said I look 'educated'!
Naw, you look like a hoodlum,
That's why everyone must think you're not.
But you just said I look lush?
True,
But a lush hoodlum.
When you beat Wali, I thought you're an ace at it.
I beat Wali for you, and you're calling me a hoodlum?
You beat him for me?
Who am I to you?
Say it straight, 'Jasmine, I'd lost my heart to you',
'I didn't like it that a hoodlum like Wali should boss over you'.
You're a Reverend's son,
At least be honest.
Anyway... It's better if you don't be honest now.
A tenant falling in love with the landlord's daughter is a classic.
I don't even believe such things...
Translation: Aditya Misra © Prime TV