♪Who were those people♪
♪Who won their love?♪
♪When obsecrating for rosebuds♪
♪I was presented with a garland of thorns...♪
♪Who were those people♪
♪Who won their love?♪
Splendid.
So to speak, she's getting married, and also not!
It's a marriage for one and not for the other.
Does she actually love someone else?
No.
She was lying about the letters and the calls.
What do you mean?
She just lied casually.
God forgive!
Ask why!
Why?
-To raise an issue of honour.
Well, that does it...
Not really.
He was delighted to hear it.
He said,
'I admire you even more now'.
'I'm proud of you'.
'You didn't conceal your past like other girls'.
So that's why the date's been fixed.
Yes.
But how can she turn back now?
You don't know her.
I do.
When she said she'd embitter us with these sweets,
She must mean it!
But
It's only four months until December.
And when I said this,
She said that this year will have 11 months,
And end without a December.
Mum!
Keep the door open
So I can hear your laughter downstairs.
Where's your brother, the loafer?
Have some shame.
Would you still call him a loafer?
What is it this time?
As if you don't know a thing!
I swear by you, I don't.
He hasn't passed away, has he?
He's got a job!
That's great!
You don't know, your father has hired him in accounts at the mill.
Oh?
He left wearing a tie,
A fine, sharp dressed gentleman!
I swear, he looked fabulous!
Sometimes, I feel he should've been born in a family like yours.
He'd wear dazzling suits,
Shining boots,
A hundred kinds of ties...
Ride a luxury car,
Attend royal parties near and far,
And have a ball.
But anyway,
Thank God
He's got a job today,
He'll prosper.
We'll have a car too,
Then I'll talk to you.
Talk -- what?
I mean, show it off, dear!
We'll meet,
'Round the lane with the Mosque,
Your car from there, ours from here,
I'd blow the horn and say,
'Move aside, mate'!
Surely, you --
Don't mind?
Not at all.
Dad used to be a supervisor in a cotton mill.
He travelled seven miles on a bicycle.
He'll find prosperity too, one day.
Cars, mansions - he'll get all he wants.
But tell him
To mind his character.
Prosperity won't be far that way.
And
Here comes my security detail.
I'll take my leave.
Bye!
Yes, Babloo?
Take it for 20.
20?
Not a penny more.
Look, Babloo.
I'm not the old Afzal anymore.
I've got a job.
One where I can't answer calls!
Look ahead!
What's before me?
My boss, Mr Chengezi, is staring at me with his eyes ablaze.
He face doesn't redden with rage,
It blackens.
Look, Babloo.
Forget me.
I'm getting used to living on my salary.
You and --
Don't use a four letter word!
I can't say one back!
Because
There's a sweet lady next to me.
Alright, bye.
You bugger!
You're the worst dastard.
Foul words!
Tell me
What'd you do before you became an accountant?
What else, sir?
Loafing around or
Bulldozing around.
But sir
I ain't that old Afzal.
If someone looked at me like that,
Like you are,
I swear by you, I would've clawed his eyes out.
But sir,
Boss is boss.
I've accepted you as mine.
Although in all honesty, you sometimes make me want to --
What!?
Leave it, sir.
You should accept it too.
I'm not the old Afzal.
What'll they think?
What?
So close since Day 1 that Rosy drove Afzal home?
Who cares?
Honestly though,
Why this inconvenience?
My home isn't too far.
For you, maybe...
Won't you be away if you go?
I think you're right.
But please,
Drop me at a slight distance.
At a distance?
-It's the neighbourhood.
Someone might think something wrong about you.
A man, yet so afraid!
I'm not a man...
W -- What?
I mean
I'm not afraid.
Women's honour is delicate.
I just care about that.
Straight ahead from here.
Excuse me.
Yes, Babloo?
It's 6.15, you bugger.
Not again!
Doesn't 20 grand make your mouth water?
It does, old chap, but --
A word's a word.
I've given Dad my word.
Alright -- Let's seal it for 25.
25?
Turn around.
Turn around? Okay...
Mr 'Turn around'!
I'll give you 30.
And if you don't take it,
Bugger off!
Turn around again.
Now,
Stop here.
Stop it, stop it!
-What?
Yes, I'm coming.
Leave me here, I'll get a rickshaw.
Mum!
It's him - Afzal!
The loafer!
How'd he get a car?
A girl's sitting in the car; she's driving.
She might be injured or something...
Oh God...
Look at him!
He left her there!
Cap'n!
Afzal's here.
The bugger.
If he hadn't come now, there would've been no gambling left in the world.
I like it.
What?
Dad can't possibly know if the match is outside the colony.
Don't drag your Dad into this.
You've got to win us this one.
Consider it done.
Modi,
Get the stuff ready.
You saw Afzal with your own eyes?
Of course.
Saw him get out of the car and run away in a rickshaw!
And you saw him with a girl?
You and your questions...
I took her to the doctor.
Do you know who she is?
Who?
Works in the accounts department at our mill.
Rosy.
Rosy?
There go all the rosy hopes!
He won't change.
What's it to you?
He's my friend's brother.
Everyone's got his eyes on him.
The poor girl...
She's got dreams because of him.
I'd gone to give her sweets,
When she told me it's his first day at work.
He's got a job at our mill in accounts.
Wow.
A job in accounts,
And a fiddle on his first day!
Fiddle?
-Isn't it?
Got the accounts officer head over heels for him on the first day.
And you!
Why'd you give her sweets?
Won't sweets be distributed now that the date's been fixed?
Mum asked me to go to the Reverend's first.
He'll give his blessings.
Oh God... Help me!
Splendid!
You bugger!
Who'll score runs for us if you let them score so many?
Come to form.
Alright.
Easy there!
Yes!
Great!
Where'd he go on a rickshaw?
What do I know?
He must've been headed home the way he ran.
He isn't here.
He's not even answering the phone.
Why would he?
He must have another one somewhere!
Another -- what?
Do I have to tell you?
Your love for God
Has blinded you to His infinite mercy on your brother.
Wait.
I'll find out.
My maid's son Eladio...
Yes?
He knows everything.
Alright, I'll wait.
Please ask him and tell me.
Okay, bye.
Hey...
Please win us this match.
I've borrowed 50,000 --
-How do I win this?
65 runs in 4 overs...
Do something.
Let me see...
Where is he?
Playing a match in the old colony.
Gambling on it?
20 in 1 over...
It's all on you now.
Why me, you bugger?
Have I ever scored 20 in 1 over?
I swear...
Go for the sixes, Afzal.
That I will, Babloo...
I'll try my best.
You gotta do this for her.
Who?
The one who writes you letters.
What was that, you bugger?
Don't you love her?
Look,
We need a six to win.
Please, mate.
Hit one.
Leave it be!
Right, show me the dough.
Yes.
Right here.
Look, I've...
Found him.
I've brought him home.
When I got there, the match
Was going on with vigour.
Ruqaiyya, I swear, if you had been by my side,
You would've sunk into the earth out of disgrace.
Labouring devotedly like an ox at an oil mill was our Afzal -
His guts haggard,
But resolve firm.
You kept on asking,
And she,
His sister, but empoisoned my ears,
That my son
Gambles!
God forgive! God forgive!
You, blear-eyed,
View pouring blood, toil, and sweat,
And striving for victory as gambling?
Look at him.
Here.
30,000 Rupees.
He's earned it.
On every banknote,
You can see my Afzal's blood and sweat if only you'd look!
Step out of the house and see,
Look at your son's trials and tribulations!
Listen to his praise echo!
You'll realise, then,
That our Afzal juggles two jobs at the same time.
Yes.
Hey!
Why are you standing?
Sit down, son.
Sit down.
My son, you...
You're standing as if you've done something wrong.
I'm the one who's been wrong, son.
I listened to them and to God...
Remained too busy with the Mosque and prayers...
And didn't shave off this sham piety and go with you.
Now, I will.
I will go with you now.
For the first time, someone else has given the call,
And I don't know
Who's led the prayers.
Enough of it all!
Enough of doing God's work.
My Afzal [excellent one] has outvied me!
He earns what he likes when he likes...
No obligations of five prayers in purity,
Nor the pain of bowing and obsecrating again and again.
I will go with you now.
Do you know how much
It hurt me
When you, so openly, took your money?
Such overt and unashamed
Gambling is not proper.
Now, when I'll be with you,
There --
Will be some secrecy.
You
Can play your match, and
I will take the money.
Hey?
What are you looking at?
Get him something to eat.
Feed him well,
Regale him.
Take this.
From now on, this responsibility, too,
Lies in your hands.
Just think that
Reverend Subhanallah is dead!
The wretch has been ensepulchred beneath the sweet redolence of banknotes!
Stop, Reverend.
By my love and purity...
Put on this turban,
And throw this wastrel out of the house.
I, too, proclaim today -
'The righteous and the sinful cannot live under one roof'.
Get out of here, you blighter!
I will take that I'd given birthed you,
Raised you, and handed you to the times.
Get out! Out!
Before my motherly affection surrenders before your sins!
Pick up your things from here,
And begone forever!
Out of my sights!
Go!
-Stop --
Stop it, Ruqaiyya.
Stop it.
It is not my desire to separate a mother from her son.
Tell him to stay here,
And keep causing me misery.
Now, if I
Separate a mother from her son,
Will God be pleased with me?
I'm faced with a difficulty on either side.
Don't turn away and leave, Reverend.
Exercise your authority as a father.
Whack him.
Slap him so hard
That the pain of it stings at him forever.
You're accosting my helplessness.
You should at least know so much
That seeing the son's temerity
Has brought tears to the father's eyes.
The courage to slap is not left in him.
Let him rot in here.
Do not proclaim greatness before fate.
For this crime of living under the same roof as him,
I shall offer
Two prayers of forgiveness.
Then, let us see what God wills.
Perhaps
Out of this pain,
He may mend his ways!
Don't worry, my dear, your name won't come up.
Forget that you told me anything.
Oh God!
What happened, sister?
I told his sister...
Mentioned your name too...
Hang up, quick!
I'm good as dead!
You won't die.
I'll ask his sister not to name you in front of him. Bye.
Hello?
Has he been caught?
Yes.
Talk about Eladio...
Oh yes --
Please,
Don't tell him Eladio ratted him out.
The poor chap's getting worried.
I won't.
What happened to your voice?
You haven't even thanked me.
Thank you.
But I request you, Lubna,
If you get wind of something like this again,
Please don't tell me.
Go now; she said she won't tell him.
Thank you.
Tell what?
And who?
You'll be delighted to hear.
The loafer Afzal --
Arifa's brother --
Yes?
I've had him nicked.
Nicked?
He was gambling on a match outside the colony.
I called Arifa and told her,
And I've come to know the Reverend's caught him in a raid.
Are you in your senses?
What have you got to do with him?
Something, certainly.
He works at our mill,
He's got the accounts officer head over heels for him,
That gives us a lot to do with him.
Now, just watch -
The Reverend will skin him alive.
Beware!
What?
Don't even mention his name!
He may be Arifa's brother,
The Reverend's son,
But I despise the very sound of his name from your mouth.
He's an A1 loafer --
And gambler.
Right...
But why do you?
I say, to the dickens with him,
It's not like I'm having an affair with him.
Arifa had pleaded before me, so I thought I'd ask Eladio.
What do I know him?
I turn away if I come across him.
Stop talking about him!
Why are you crying now?
I'm wicked, am I not?
Yes.
You're wicked.
You made Dad cry.
Now, even a lifetime of weeping
Cannot possibly recompense those tears.
Listen.
Remember this...
I'll weep all my life,
But find peace only when I have recompensed those tears.
I'm serving dinner; come and have some.
I'll die of hunger but not have a bite.
I went to office,
Having decided
That I won't gamble again.
But that blighter Babloo --
Kept on calling, and I kept telling him that I won't play.
But --
I fell for the lure of 30,000.
He's not a blighter,
I'm the blighter!
If I had the slightest hint
That Dad would cry like this if he found out,
I'd never have played.
I swear by you.
If you think
I'm lying under my oath by you,
Then I'm not wicked,
I'm the most vile and dastardly.
Alright...
Have something to eat...
I'll talk to Dad if you have some food.
I've never given an assurance.
I've got a feeling he'll forgive you.
I'll have something.
Give us our lives, O Gracious Lord, in Your Surrender, and admit into the Safety of Your Peace.
You come with an endorsement?
I've come to assure you.
He swore by my head for the first time.
I swear today that he won't gamble again.
He won't smoke cigarettes or weed.
He'll be honest and principled in his work.
He was weeping because you had shed tears.
I said that even a lifetime of weeping cannot possibly recompense Dad's tears.
And he said,
'I'll weep all my life'
'But find peace only when I have atoned for them'.
Will he pray?
We'll know at daybreak.
Just forgive him. Don't strike a deal.
I forgive him.
Come on. Have dinner with him.
With the unfaithful liar!
With the redeemed.
I agree to what you say.
But remember
He'll finish you off as well
Where there won't be the slightest relief. Yes.
Hey, Afzal!
You bugger!
I heard you won 30,000 yesterday?
Secretly earnin' your riches, eh?
Hey, Afzal!
It's him.
Whatever his character may be like,
You got to admit he's got those looks!
Hey!
What happened to your head?
Got injured.
Your heart was injured... But you've bandaged your head!
It's a real one, innit?
I've had an accident, sir.
Why am I not surprised?
Let's see where it's hurt him.
Excuse me, sir?
There's no costing or budgeting in love.
You never know how much you may end up spending.
It must've cost 10,000.
What?
Getting the car repaired, of course.
No. Just 2,500.
So to speak, the first meeting cost you 2,500.
-Good morning! Good morning, sir!
Good morning... Morning, Sir!
'Morning. Very good morning.
Why don't I see your wound?
Perhaps you've been hurt on the inside?
Miss Rosy?
What happened to you?
You got injured?
Yes.
But how?
You were fine in the evening.
I had the accident in the evening!
A car hit me from behind when I was taking a U-turn!
You may leave.
Would you happen to have a pen?
I'd like some tea.
Translation: Aditya Misra © Prime TV