♪Who were those people♪
♪Who won their love?♪
♪When obsecrating for rosebuds♪
♪I was presented with a garland of thorns...♪
♪Who were those people♪
♪Who won their love?♪
Thought of a name?
No good.
Who'd meet my family?
Gotta start with someone.
Shut up.
Okayyy... What's it to me anyway?
But what'll you do about Mum?
She'll ask you when he's coming the moment you reach home.
I've got my answer.
Tell me.
He's out of town.
He's in Karachi.
Right...
That's good.
But then, Dad will ask for his number.
Gee, I feel like crashing into a wall!
Hmm...
Can't be much better than Mehtab.
Just crash into Mehtab and marry him!
Not Karachi.
America.
Don't drag America into this.
It's aready got its hands full with its own share of quandaries!
Just try to understand!
I'll say he's gone to America.
He'll be back in a few days.
And if he isn't?
I'm sure I can find someone in a few days.
She'll also ask why you didn't take the driver along.
Be ready with your answer.
It's him, isn't it?
Arifa's brother?
You're right...
But what's he doing here?
He should be at the office right now.
He's an A1 loafer.
Skiving off again, I'm sure.
You left the driver here when you left?
I nearly forgot -- Just realised --
I'd left the driver at home...
You haven't even mentioned when he's coming.
Sometime after the evening.
But not for -- a couple of days...
Why?
He's -- Out of the country.
Where is he?
I don't know --
He had a few options...
He'll tell me once he's there -- where he is!
I'm sure we can call him?
I'm sure, when your father is satisfied...
He hasn't slept peacefully all night.
Turning from one side to another,
He'd say with visible fear
As he glimpsed the gun,
'Get this gun off the wall'!
Get it off then...
It's not about the gun.
Your Dad is unsettled.
He was asking his name over breakfast.
What could I tell him?
You haven't even told me!
He was mumbling as he smoked his cigar in the morning,
Saying, 'I don't even know his name',
'And he's gonna be my son-in-law'!
Just a couple of days, Mum...
Everyone will get to know him.
I -- I'm not hungry at all.
Ask Aunt not to knock on our door.
Wait!
At least tell me his name!
I'll tell your father when he'd ask -
'Make do with just the name for now',
'You'll get to know the rest later'.
Tell me. What's his name?
Afzal...
You didn't mention what happened to her...
It's nothing.
Nothing?
Why is she unconscious for so long then?
-It's a shock.
Perhaps she's suddenly heard some news, or...
Or?
Are you, by any chance, getting her married to someone she doesn't like?
Don't tell me you could find that out too.
No, I can't,
But I'm a family doctor. This is why I'm asking.
Yes, it was planned...
We'd fixed the date too,
But then found out she's not happy with it.
What did you do?
What a good father should've done.
I'll call to decline today.
Good.
Tell your family not to utter his name before her.
What's his name, by the way?
Mehtab.
What a nice name!
Anyway, she'll come to soon.
Don't meet her before she's stable.
Why?
In such cases, every decent girl fears her father.
Okay.
I won't meet her.
Who's this Afzal, Lubna?
What's she asking?
She's asking who Afzal is.
But why's she asking? She ought to tell us!
The truth is,
It's gotten into her mind
That I didn't mention his full name.
Isn't it his full name?
No.
His name ain't even Afzal!
I meant --
'Afzal'
As in 'the best'.
What do you mean?
Not his name!
I meant his character.
He's the best in character.
There's no one like him, really!
Well...
I can understand that.
By the Lord, for a while, I thought
You're talking about Reverend Subhanallah's son.
God forgive!
God is the Greatest...
Farah!
Farah, wake up!
Get up! Mum's left!
Peace and Mercy of God be upon you...
God forgive all my sins...
O our Lord, give us good in this world and good in the Hereafter, and protect us from the punishment of the hell fire.
Who's this Afzal?
That blighter?
Reverend Subhanallah's son?
The loafer, the vagrant!
You named him and said I love him!
That's what you think about me!
You thought you'd name anyone,
And I'd stay quiet!
Just because I'm in the soup?
To the dickens with it!
I'd much rather be in the soup
Than out with the help of that loafer extraordinaire!
But if you mentioned his name again,
I'll claw your face apart!
Listen to me, Farah.
I changed my statement.
Mum, too, had thought I was talking about Reverend Subhanallah's son.
So?
Who were you talking about?
I was saying that he had the best character.
Unrivalled, unlike any other!
Oh my God...
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
I'm so wicked, am I not?
I slapped you so hard...
I'm sorry.
Please...
Hey!
What took you so long?
Greetings, Mum!
That's great!
You've finished your lunch.
Hold on.
What's the matter?
Why aren't you saying anything?
We'd asked you to become a good man.
Don't become so good that we start fearing you.
I'm going to look for my degrees and certificates.
No idea where I kept them.
Why do you need them now?
I've gotten a job on Dad's recommendation,
But that can't prove I'm a BA.
Oh...
May I go and look for them now?
Don't.
All your documents are in Dad's cupboard.
I'll get you everything in a while.
Get me some tea.
Right away!
Come, Monseigneur. It's time for the 9 p.m. news bulletin.
I know.
Switch it off, will you?
What's the matter, Monseigneur?
Something bothering you?
Nothing wrong as such,
But it weighs on my heart to remember whatever's been said...
She's come to now.
Had her dinner.
If you have any suspicions or fears,
Call and tell her openly.
I'm not talking about her.
Who are you talking about?
I mean --
Reverend Subhanallah's son...
What's his name?
Afzal?
Yes, Afzal.
No way.
It's not like that.
Even I thought she was talking about him.
But found out later that
She was just talking about his character.
I'm talking about his character too.
I found out today that he was harassing our Accounts Officer.
Thumbed a lift from her and tried to assault her in her car!
The blighter!
Look at him!
That's what the son of a priest is doing!
I say, throw him out!
So I did.
But I'm regretting it.
But why?
Feel good,
For you did the right thing.
If the Reverend's reputation is the cause of your regret,
Tell him when you meet him,
'That's what your son's like'!
Only... That's not what he's like.
I feel that's not what he's like.
I've seen that type.
No one like that
Speaks before his boss with such firmness,
Nor kicks away a job he got mere days before, saying, 'Please tell my father'.
'I, too, want to see how much Dad distrusts me'.
I've asked about her.
Just 15 minutes ago, I got news that she was having dinner with Chengezi at a restaurant.
Chengezi is my Chief Accountant.
He's the one who issued the memo to him.
If that's so, why don't you reinstate him?
I would, but will he come back?
I don't think so.
This is your BA degree,
Your FA [A-Level] certificate,
And this one's for your matric [GCSEs],
And your character certificate.
Shall I massage your head?
No.
Not today.
Why not?
It's this massage
That's got your grey cells working!
I need just so many grey cells to work
For me to go on like I am.
Aww, frustrated because you're a clerk?
Don't be.
Great men have humble beginnings.
Do you know about what Abraham Lincoln was?
Or what Edison used to do?
Let's talk about me, Arifa.
I'll never become a great man.
So Hazrat Sahab used to lie?
Mum tells me
He'd seat you in his lap
And say, 'You'll see, Subhanallah',
'He'll grow to become a great man one day'!
Don't laugh like that.
Hazrat Sahab didn't lie.
It's just gotten into you that you can never become a great man.
Who's this Afzal?
That blighter?
Reverend Subhanallah's son?
The loafer, the vagrant!
You named him and said I love him!
That's what you think about me!
You thought you'd name anyone,
And I'd stay quiet!
Just because I'm in the soup?
To the dickens with it!
I'd much rather be in the soup
Than out with the help of that loafer extraordinaire! But if you mentioned his name again, I'll claw your face apart!
Who is it?
Still angry with me?
Okay.
How about you slap me?
Oh, please...
Slap my elder sister?
The one I've taken is enough.
There, now.
Sorry.
I promise. I won't ever slap you again.
Leave it be, Farah.
Just tell me
Why do you despise Afzal so much?
I don't despise Afzal.
Just -- Who is he?
He's my best friend's elder brother.
And you know how nice she is.
I also know
That the Reverend is a good man.
But look at him!
How can the two of us judge what someone's like?
You'll scold me now
That I'm naming him.
But please, try not to.
Tell me, logically speaking,
How can we know what someone's like
Or what one's like when we hear about them?
I have a simple logic.
He's nobody to me.
Yes,
I found out two days ago
That he works at our mill.
Okay, he's our employee.
A slacker, at that!
Remember?
He was out in the grounds watching a cricket match during office hours!
He's no longer our employee, Farah.
Dad's ousted him.
Miss Rosy filed a complaint against him over harassment.
Perturbed over it, Dad was out in the courtyard for an hour.
Why?
Because he felt after he came home that he wasn't the culprit after all.
He was cursing himself.
Who told you?
Mum.
She also told me he didn't have his dinner.
Then Dad does not know
That I saw him come out of Rosy's car with my own eyes.
The poor girl must've given him a lift,
And he would've thought he's got her head over heels for him.
Yes...
That may have caused the accident.
She must've been defending herself.
Please go and tell Dad.
Okay, I will.
And please bother to listen to anything he says.
Hey! What'll he say?
-What could a regretful man say?
Mum said he'd apologise to him
If he could have his way.
And beg forgiveness of Reverend Subhanallah.
If that's so, why not ask him to come back?
Reinstate him?
He's not coming back, Farah.
Why not?
He's Reverend Subhanallah's son.
Kicked away the job he'd gotten on recommendation.
Know what,
When he used to gamble over matches,
Arifa would tell me about it.
But she never said,
'My brother is the type who doesn't respect women'.
I asked once
That there must be someone he loves.
She said, 'I'm sure there's someone',
'But he never tells anyone her name'.
Where's he gone?
To meet his friends?
He'll just have a little chat and come back.
When will he be back?
Before you go to bed.
Meet me somewhere else, my sweeting,
This pauper's presence in this princely concourse is not proper;
For souls besotted with love to walk upon
These trails etched with the marks of regality is not proper;
This meadow on this bank of the Yamuna [holy river], this château
These sculptured doors and walls, these arches, these niches -
An Emperor, by the weight of his wealth,
Has but made sport of the love of the penurious...
My sweeting,
Meet me somewhere else.
No.
I won't smoke.
I'll have some tea.
Would you look at that!
It's him, isn't it? Arifa's brother?
Yeah...
But what's he doing here?
He's an A1 loafer.
Skiving off again, I'm sure.
It's him!
Who?
Afzal!
Stop by the cart.
I'll have some of this roasted corn.
How much?
As much as you like!
Look behind us!
Is he coming?
Afzal?
Of course!
No.
He will.
Here he comes!
Which way is he going?
The other way.
Did you see that?
What?
-He's not headed for our office!
Our office is that way.
Listen!
Call him back yourself.
He may come back if you ask him.
Alright, I'll call him.
And if he doesn't come back, talk to the Reverend in the evening.
Get this weight off your heart.
If he doesn't come when I ask him, I'm not talking to the Reverend.
What difference does it make?
-It does make one.
It just struck me...
The way he said confidently,
'Please tell my father about this'.
But now, I don't know what I'd say to his father.
Mr Afzal Subhanallah!
Come.
Afzal...
Subhanallah?
Yes.
Matric [GCSEs]...
FA [A-Levels] and BA...
Third division throughout.
But your character certificate is remarkable.
Third division folks...
Aren't usually so remarkable.
How come you're so good?
Any experience?
Two days as an accountant at Ibrahim Cottons.
Not a very good experience.
For them or for you?
For both of us.
Can you speak English?
I can understand what's written.
Speak a little, too.
Tell us the story of the thirsty crow.
Sir?
Thirsty crow, my dear chap.
Don't you remember?
'Once upon a time, there was a crow who was very thirsty'...
Do you know English?
What do you mean?
That's what I'm saying -
'What do you mean'?
I'll tell this one to my friends now -
'There was a crow'
'Who was really hungry'.
Hello?
Am I talking to Afzal?
Yes?
Sheikh Ibrahim here.
Peace be upon you, sir.
And upon you, peace.
Look, my dear, I realised later that it was not your fault.
I regret admonishing you over it.
No, sir.
There's nothing to regret.
It's okay.
I'd like you to come back.
Come and take your place at our office.
Thank you, sir.
But forgive me, sir.
It doesn't please me to take up a job on Dad's recommendation.
Perhaps you're --
-No, sir.
No 'perhaps' here.
Dad wanted me to get a job so I could correct my ways.
His desire has been fulfilled.
I've corrected my ways.
I walk from place to place in search of a job now.
It's made me aware of my father's hardships.
And, in all honesty, once one has corrected his ways, he does not take up a job on recommendation.
Thank you very much, sir.
Yes, sir?
How many children do you have?
Three, sir...?
Two sons,
And one daughter.
How old is your daughter?
12, sir.
And Miss Rosy?
How many children does she have?
No, sir...
She's not even married.
Give Miss Rosy three months' worth of compensation,
And out her.
Sir?
If you 'Sir' me again, I'll issue the same orders for you.
Right, sir.
Promise me
You'll never mention her again,
Nor will you ask her name.
Just think as if
There's no one...
No name...
Just... A dream...
That delights me when I imagine it...
And if this isn't acceptable either,
Go and ask for Dad's opinion on it.
If delighting myself with a dream is sinful,
I will not.
Don't go this way.
We go this way everyday.
Turn right, will you?
I know a shortcut.
Right, how's everything?
Fine.
Is it time for your break now?
It will be in a couple of minutes...
Have your lunch properly.
I will.
I've cleaned your room.
Thank you.
I...
Found the key to your cupboard.
Key?
Don't worry. I didn't see anything.
Where'd you find it?
Don't ask me. I didn't even have to look for it.
That's my treasure in your possession!
That is why I stopped short of unlocking it.
Stopped?
I thought I'd open and read all the letters.
But then thought...
God's watching.
Please
Keep on fearing God.
Alright, bye.
Have your lunch.
Right away...
Translation: Aditya Misra © Prime TV