♪Who were those people♪
♪Who won their love?♪
♪When obsecrating for rosebuds♪
♪I was presented with a garland of thorns...♪
♪Who were those people♪
♪Who won their love?♪
Here's your tea.
Hey!
Yes?
Did he pray at daybreak?
I went to wake him up. Smiled in his sleep as he glimpsed me.
I thought he was dreaming, so I thought I'd let him.
I'll wake him up at daybreak tomorrow.
I'll get you into University this time.
Ask him when gets back to check when the admissions open.
But what about
Co-education?
What's the big deal?
Maintaining one's decency is in one's own hands.
You come across men even in the markets.
That's co-education too,
So, to speak.
Dad!
I know when the admissions open.
When?
The 25th of the next month.
Right.
Would you serve some food? I'm starving.
Where's Mum?
Sleeping in her room. Shall I rouse her?
No.
Let her sleep.
Who's calling you repeatedly?
No idea.
It's an unknown number.
Calls again if I disconnect. He's called me some 10 times since the morning.
Talk to him.
I will for real.
So what?
Do you feel like insulting someone?
Hello?
Where's Farah?
Why isn't she answering the phone?
Who's on the line?
You forgot me? Didn't even recognise my voice...
Will you keep on with this blather or tell who you are?
It's Mehtab, Lubna...
Oh, Mehtab...
Where's Farah?
I've been trying her number. She's not answering.
She keeps her phone on silent mode at the University.
Want to talk to her?
-Yes, please.
I thought she would've called me by the time I reached Karachi.
Here, Farah. It's Mehtab.
Hello?
It's Mehtab, Farah.
I know.
Didn't you think of me?
I did.
But I couldn't figure how I'd talk to Dad.
Talk?
To Dad?
What?
You'll know within minutes when I've talked to him.
Dad'll be calling you first.
So,
How go the preparations for the wedding?
Whose wedding?
Very funny.
I like this one.
Ain't no joke.
I'm seriously asking you -
Whose wedding are you talking about?
Ours, dear, of course!
I find it awkward to answer such a question.
Ohh...
The one planned for the 15th of December...
You're talking about that, right?
Again, very funny.
You're angry because I didn't call you when I got here?
Just ask why.
I was waiting that you would --
-Look, Mehtab.
It would hurt you to know,
But let me be very honest with you -
This proposal is unacceptable!
You're talking about the 15th of December?
Well, that December will never come!
Or it won't have a 15th!
Such fury!
Forgive me.
I was wrong.
What?
I was so blimming wrong!
I should've told you before you'd left.
But it's alright. I'll tell you now.
Our second meeting on the terrace
Was our last meeting.
L -- Last meeting?
La finale!
Is it something Mehtab said?
No.
Something I said...
-Go on.
I told him I'm not marrying him.
That this proposal is unacceptable...
No matter the cost...
Then suffer the consequences.
What consequences?
An earful from Dad,
And you won't be able to stand Mum's ululation!
I don't worry so much about Mum...
But Dad --
-Dad may even slap you!
Oh God!
What have I done?
What if he draws his gun?
Gun?
Don't you remember?
He'd drawn his gun when Aunt...
And fired too.
It's another thing no one got hit...
But that can't happen every time...
Where are you going?
To my room.
Hide in my room.
But why?
Going before them is dangerous.
You may get hit
Where you won't need a second bullet.
Afzal!
Come here. Get in.
Whose car is this?
My brother's.
Get in, quick.
Don't ask too many questions.
No.
I'm fine.
I'll walk. Thank you.
Why are you saying 'Thank you'?
C'mon, get in!
I've decided to ride a car home
Only when I own one.
How will you own one?
Clerks don't get to own cars.
[Call to prayer]
Farah...
Don't you think you're taking it for granted?
As, say, with a wedding.
When you're invited to one,
You accept it with delight.
And then think,
'I'll attend if I can spare time',
'Otherwise, I'll call and say, "Sorry, mate, I'm busy".'
And, as it happens,
You're done for.
Don't remind me my mistakes!
I'm no Mehtab Chawla
To think we have an 'understanding' if you scold me.
Please, Lubna,
I've realised my mistakes.
I should've rejected the proposal before they left.
And if I could not,
Then I shouldn't have phoned Mehtab and said,
'This proposal is unacceptable'!
You're regretting what you did?
Obviously.
I should've talked to Mum instead of Mehtab Chawla.
No, Madame, you should've talked to Dad.
What?
Talking to Mum will get you nowhere.
She'll just say,
'Monseigneur, this girl will drag you through the mire'!
And Dad will actually drag me through a mire!
No way. Dad's not like that.
He'll be a bit furious to hear it.
But then ask sternly,
'Is that your final decision'?
Sure?
Be positive!
Just think as if that's going to happen.
Show some sensibility,
And when he asks
If it's your final decision,
Say firmly:
'Yes, Dad. It's my final decision'.
So he won't slap me?
Good fathers don't slap their young daughters.
Surely he'll ask the reason?
Reason?
-He'll surely ask what Mehtab's fault had been.
And, in that case,
Why I'd not mentioned it before the date was fixed or before he left.
That's right...
He'll surely ask you that...
What'll you say?
You tell me.
I'm totally blank. I don't know.
Oh yes!
Say the same you did to Mehtab!
What did I say to Mehtab?
'I love someone else',
'We used to write letters back in the day, and now we talk for hours on the phone'.
Say that to Dad?
No. Say that to Mum.
What about the mire, then?
Don't worry.
You'd be neck-deep in the mire by then.
I mean
You would've said to Dad that you don't want to marry Mehtab.
He'll ask why.
Tell him you'd only tell Mum.
Yes. That's possible.
But when do I say this?
Before he watches the news.
I wonder why...
-Easy.
There's all sorts of bad news on the TV,
Your news will be the icing on the cake.
Good Lord, he'll think you're Kamikaze attacking him.
Mademoiselle Farah,
Yes?
Monseigneur wants you downstairs.
Yes, Dad?
Sit.
You talked to Mehtab today?
Yes, Dad.
He called.
What did you say when he mentioned the marriage?
Tell me. What did you say?
I -- said
That this proposal is unacceptable.
Was it something he said?
Not at all -- he just wanted to talk.
If you'd rather that he not call you before the marriage,
I can ask him not to.
It's not about that, Dad...
What is it, then?
The thing is --
The fault -- was mine.
I should've --
Told you earlier.
What is it that you
Should've told me earlier?
That I --
I don't want to marry Mehtab.
-Couldn't you say it before the date was decided?
Are you bent on dragging us through the mire?
Don't worry about that.
Just tell me the reason.
I'll tell Mum the reason...
Come with me, then.
What did she say?
She will not marry Mehtab.
Call Mehtab and convey this rejection.
Say that it's not possible now.
Why not?
She loves someone else.
Who?
Should I ask her that too?
Obviously.
It isn't something I can ask.
Get all the details from her.
Who he is, what he does,
Where he lives,
His family background. Everything.
What do you mean?
Try to understand, Irsa Begum.
This isn't 1992
That I could impose my will at gunpoint.
If she does not want to marry Mehtab,
That's okay.
I will decline the proposal.
But first, find out more about him.
What's his status, family background, and character like?
A tad here or there in rank and status is fine by me.
But I will not compromise
On family background and character.
Go to sleep.
How do I fall asleep?
Then brace yourself,
For you'll be asked in a while
Who you love
Who he is,
What's his status and rank,
What does he do,
What's his character like?
Bolt the door.
Bolt the door, please.
And if anyone asks,
Say, 'She dropped dead the moment she came in'!
It's time for dinner.
Bon appétit!
I mean -- Serve everyone.
Farah's not hungry.
You're not hungry either?
Why are you asking questions?
Go and say that Lubna's not having dinner either.
Why don't you go?
Go and see how everything is going on!
Don't be crazy,
Sleep on quietly.
If anyone asks, I'll say you took sleeping pills.
What'll that do?
Buy some time!
Think about his name, address, family, and character.
If there's no one,
Imagine there is.
Name him,
Think about his family
And take it for a given
That all of Hyderabad is in awe of his character.
If I keep on lying like this,
What'll happen to my character?
Then, there's just one way out.
Which is?
Tell the truth and marry Mehtab.
No way!
Then let untruth be your master and say anything you like.
Worrying about your character will ruin your life.
Shall we go up to the terrace?
-What's up there?
You just have to lie.
Sit here and prepare yourself.
If you gad about everywhere, you'd be caught with your pants down!
I'll take whatever comes my way.
Do you know how happy Dad was today?
I know.
You don't.
He said, 'Apply to a University'.
What?
No way --
I swear by you.
It's a golden opportunity, Afzal.
Yes.
Why, sure. Do it.
I'll pay your fees.
I'm not talking about admissions and fees.
Then?
Tell me about her.
Who?
The girl who writes letters to you.
Just tell me her name and address. I'll talk to Dad.
What'd you talk about?
Won't you marry her?
I'll ask Dad to talk to her family.
First, ask -
Will she marry me?
As if she writes letters to you just for fun!
Let's just say she does.
My marriage to her isn't possible.
So,
Promise me
You'll never mention her again,
Nor will you ask her name.
Just think as if
There's no one...
No name...
Just... A dream...
That delights me when I imagine it...
And if this isn't acceptable either,
Go and ask for Dad's opinion on it.
Ask him.
If delighting myself with a dream is sinful,
I will not.
Are you friends with anyone from your University?
Shut up!
Do I ever make friends with anyone?
A class fellow
Who could be let in on it and asked for help?
Don't even think about it!
Farhad!
Aunt Mahjabeen's son?
-Yes!
He'll agree in an instant!
What else do we want?
Are you touched in the head?
If I name someone from the family,
I'd have to get married to him.
God forgive me,
But he's worse than Mehtab!
Don't put up a blank face, missy, find a way out!
Who's talking about his face?
Aunt would've set up camp here
Before I've even mentioned his name!
He should be the type
Who stands firm for four months,
And vanishes in a flash as the moment of the marriage approaches.
Oh God, very theatrical!
So what if it is theatrical?
I'm not marrying Mehtab.
No.
My heart doesn't agree to it.
In fact, it isn't just about the heart.
My mind asks me to be wary!
Alright, how about Aunt Mehru's Jamil Akhtar?
You've officially gone barmy!
Don't even think about anyone from the family.
Who, then?
You're not on speaking terms with anyone outside,
You haven't got eyes for anyone in the family,
Then you've got no option except Barack Obama.
What can that poor fellow do?
Launch a drone attack on Mehtab's house and resolve the entire matter in a flash.
Where are you off to now?
Where would I go?
I'm just checking why Aunt hasn't come yet.
Why would she come?
Splendid.
She's going to come and tell you that Dad's calling you.
Look who we have here!
The Reverend's son.
The bugger's turned into a Reverend himself!
You bugger!
What am I hearing?
I'm getting late for work,
We'll talk when we meet later.
When are we meeting?
You're turning your friends down
For some twopenny-halfpenny job?
It's not like that,
I promise we'll meet tonight.
He's lying!
He's not coming!
His Dad's had him swear that he'll never meet Timmy and Sajid!
Innit?
That's the matter, right?
No. That's not what it's like.
You've got to change yourself to do a job.
I've heard you've stopped playing matches.
I'll play.
But I won't gamble on it.
Why don't you just say you've been ensnared in your Dad's sermons!
I've been ensnared in Dad's sermons!
Seeing what I do brought tears to his eyes!
I can't bear to see his tears.
I'm wicked,
But not flagitious.
The sun's come up!
It's 9 already!
Oh my God...
Thank God!
You'll be thrown out of the University!
Get ready quick, Farah! Double time!
I'm thankful it ended there!
Mum must've explained everything.
And Dad must've decided, too
'Even if she loves someone',
'We'll talk some other day'.
I'll offer two additional prayers when I'm back
In fact, I'll offer all my prayers!
What are you looking at?
Go to your room and get ready, quick!
I'm going!
I know I'm late!
Good morning!
I've called to apologise.
Mum called and told me
I was left screaming in horror; after all, it's between us; we'll resolve it together.
Where's your Mum?
No --
I swear, it's not Mum's fault either.
It's just she talked to a friend, and --
She suggested it.
Where's your Mum's friend?
Hey!
You don't even know her.
Besides,
What will you say to her?
I'll thank her.
Say a big 'Thank you' to her.
And
Thank you very much too!
I was growing anxious how I could talk about it to Mum and Dad.
So sweet of you!
Alright, now...
I'm getting late for my classes!
Peace be upon you.
Please sign this photocopy
And confirm the receipt of this letter.
Letter?
It's a memo.
What's a memo?
You'll find out when you read it.
Read it after you've signed this.
Please don't talk to me about anything!
Talk to me!
I've signed the memo.
What's this you've written?
That I t -- tease Miss Rosy, I --
Pester her, harrass her?
Can you see this?
Miss Rosy has complained against you.
Look at me, young man!
I've been easy on you when writing that.
Miss Rosy had even said
That she fears for her honour around you!
Around me?
Over here!
I've even come to know the thing about the injury.
Be thankful
I did not write that Fescennine story in the memo!
Fescennine story?
The thing about the injury --
What about the injury?
Have some shame.
You thumb a lift from a girl,
And try to assault her?
I'm ashamed to think of it!
You're the son of a priest.
Look at your father's dignity and honour, and fear for yourself!
Yes?
Yes sir.
Coming, sir.
Come.
Where?
Monseigneur has called you.
And beware!
Don't you dare lie to him!
Come.
Listen, Farah.
Come here.
Yes, Mum?
Tell him to come and meet your father.
Who?
What's his name?
Name?
Don't be afraid.
Your father said that if he's from a good family and of good character, he has no problem.
A tad here or there in rank and status is fine by him.
I told you, you've nothing to fear.
Call him here.
You don't believe me, do you?
Alright,
Go to University for now; call me when you believe me and tell me when he'll be coming.
It'd be better if he came in the evening.
Get a move on!
What is this?
It's all a lie, sir.
I want her here, Mr Chengezi.
Please wait, sir...
Why are you calling her here?
So that she can say all of this to my face?
I accept that she would've said it.
And I accept that Mr Chengezi reported it to you because she'd said it.
But I want to ask one thing, sir.
If her words are taken for the truth, why is what I say necessarily false?
I saw you get in the car with her with my own eyes.
And that bandage on her head - she's shown me the wound.
A wound half an inch wide!
Does that prove I'm lying, sir?
Do you know where you're standing?
And who you're blabbing before?
I've come to realise today where I stand, sir.
I can do nothing but say that I'm not the culprit.
You may pronounce whatever decision you see fit.
I have great respect for your father.
He leads my prayers.
I'd given you this job on his request.
Do you know what he'd said when he recommended you?
He would've said, 'My son is not virtuous, sir'.
'He gambles on matches, smokes weed with his vagabond friends'.
But he wouldn't have said, 'My son does not respect the dignity and honour of women'.
That's one vice I don't have, sir.
Perhaps, trusting my inculpability from this transgression, my father used to forgive every trespass of mine.
I hereby resign from this job, sir.
For the first time, I am not the offender.
But I've got a feeling I am.
Please do mention this crime of mine when you meet Dad.
I, too, want to see, sir,
How much Dad distrusts me.
With peace, sir.
He's just being dramatic, sir.
Did you
Wake him up at daybreak?
I didn't need to!
He was praying when I entered his room.
He's awakened now, Dad.
There's no need to knock and wake him up now.
Do you
Remember Hazrat Sahib?
Of course.
When he was young,
He used to seat him in his lap.
He loved him so much.
He would turn his gaze to me and say,
'Remember, Subhanallah',
'He'll grow to become a great man one day'.
Take him to his grave someday
And say to him, 'Bless you'.
'What you said has come true'.
With blessings, your son has become a clerk.
Oh, please, Ruqaiyya Begum...
That's how everything starts.
A tree does not grow tall in one day.
Take me, for example.
When I got married to you,
What was I?
And what are you now?
You just became a priest, Reverend.
You couldn't become a great man.
There is no other power [but God's]!
Hello?
Hello!
How are you, sire?
How goes your job?
Good!
Very good!
Ohh...
You're speaking English to proclaim your majesty!
My dear, show your majesty through your work. Many can speak English 'round here.
I'm working very hard...
What's that noise?
Noise --?
The TV's on.
Mr Chengezi has a thing for the matches.
So he's just like you!
Yes.
When's the break?
Break?
I mean when do you have your lunch?
Why don't you ask straight away?
I have my lunch when I'm hungry.
Hey? It's 2 p.m!
You're not feeling hungry?
-Oh?
It's 2 already?
Alright. Quickly now, have your lunch.
I know you've got a lot of work. Keep on doing it.
But take care of your health.
I'll eat in a while.
And remember to offer your midday prayers.
Dad feels good to hear about it.
I will.
Alright.
Bye.
Translation: Aditya Misra © Prime TV