♪Who were those people♪
♪Who won their love?♪
♪When obsecrating for rosebuds♪
♪I was presented with a garland of thorns...♪
♪Who were those people♪
♪Who won their love?♪
10,000 will be enough to provide both of them with food,
And we'd be making a profit of 10,000!
He was up to his trickery, offering the old 8,000.
I said, 'Watch who you're talking to'!
And he,
The one from Hyderabad!
I gave him a right scolding.
I even said, 'You have a bad reputation in Mam's eyes'!
'Shut your gob'!
Is he married?
Doesn't seem so, judging by his words,
Although someone his age should get married.
I saw him yesterday.
He does look lush.
So what if he looks lush?
He's very insolent, by the way.
Took him two days to start a slanging match!
The way he addresses me with a simple 'you'!
How else should he address you?
Hey!
I'm his landlady,
He should say 'Madam' or 'Lady' at the very least!
Seems he's from a good family.
I'll ask him this one, too.
What?
'Do you come from a good family, or is it just Mam who thinks so'?
Don't you dare ask him anything like this!
Well, I can ask Babu Hamid about this too.
But what have we to do with his family?
As long as he quietly enjoys his food, pays us the money, and keeps fearing God!
Can you read it in anyone's face? About his family?
You can't, can you?
Ugh...
Potatoes and lentils again?
Don't worry.
We'll get chicken on Sundays.
Enough, Salim,
Enough!
What?
Just -- What!?
Sit down.
-How many times will you ask me?
It's Saturday today.
-You already know everything!
Tell me everything!
Tell me!
Be honest with me,
Did he ever touch you?
Never!
He used to say, 'Touching besmirches love'.
Oh?
Blimmin' son of a saint!
And you! You're praising him before me!
The blighter's here.
Tell her
It's our personal matter.
She better not poke her nose in our affairs!
Yes, sir?
Why is your husband beating you?
Look, sir,
It is our personal matter.
No --
It doesn't remain personal when you scream like that.
Who are you?
I --
Live just across here
With Babu Hamid.
Please, leave,
And take it that it was my fault.
Listen, sir!
Yes?
Have you come from Hyderabad?
Afzal, is it?
It is.
Hey!
What are you doing, Timmy?
Let go!
Where is he?
Who?
Afzal.
He played his last match with you.
Match, as in, gambling.
For 100,000, no less.
Where'd he go after that?
Karachi.
Where in Karachi?
I don't know.
Press harder!
Seriously, Timmy, I don't know anything!
I just dropped him at the station, that's it!
I even said, 'Don't go'!
But he doesn't listen to anyone, now, does he?
Let him go.
He must call you sometimes.
His phone's switched off.
He must've gotten a new number.
Go and ask his family, will you?
I'm sure he calls them!
He doesn't.
The Reverend came to me.
Asked how everything was going,
But, as he left, he said,
'Does Afzal talk to you'?
I said, 'Not at all'.
'His number's switched off'.
He was a bit dispirited to hear this
And said, 'Ah, yes, his number's switched off'...
Go, now.
If you hear from him... Just let us know, okay?
Sure.
I won't keep you waiting!
Why aren't you eating anything?
I will if I learn.
Learn what?
Please, go on.
I'm watching and learning
How one can swallow a bite like this.
Do you actually eat it, or do you just put up a pretence for me?
I'll try, too, today.
If you keep on trying,
I'll have to call the doctor.
And he charges more for coming here.
The rest is up to you.
I'd gone to Karachi two years ago.
I don't even remember if that blasted sea is where it used to be,
Or has it, too, skedaddled...
How far is Karachi anyway?
We can go again.
But
Where will we look for him?
The city's as large as a country.
Is it too big for a mother's heart?
I can find my son with eyes both shut, Reverend.
Alright, then.
Make ready to leave.
We can leave
Any day you pick.
But remember,
A defeated mother's son
Can never triumph himself.
Call Arifa and ask her
To send a picture of him.
Right,
What'd you do with it?
Hey!
What'd I do with it?
We can help them.
How?
We'll run an ad on TV.
That --
'A 32-year-old has run away from home, embarrassed'.
With Arifa's voiceover
In a melancholic voice -
'Come home, my dear',
'Everyone's distressed',
'Dad's quietened up',
'Mum's not eating anything in her sorrow'.
You'll see,
He'll come back running!
What if he actually came?
So what?
May he come back with the Lord's blessings,
Stay at home,
And take care of his Mum and Dad.
Where will you go for your MPhil?
You haven't got a chance in Hyderabad.
How does that even relate
To me doing my MPhil?
When I said
I'm not going to London,
What does it mean?
That's what I'm asking.
Dad will talk to me tonight.
He'll ask, 'What's Farah up to'?
Why would he ask you?
Am I dead?
Well,
Even if he wants to ask you,
Just say,
That I'm going to Karachi. Willy nilly.
Should I call now?
Call who?
Arifa.
Oh, right.
I'll ask the driver to get the picture from her.
Talk to her.
Get the picture.
But that blighter won't come back just like that.
You're right.
He'd only come back if someone showed up at his doorstep,
Grabbed his collar, and said a few foul words to awaken his conscience.
No.
Just get a picture.
One should keep all possible options in mind,
Right?
Hello?
How are you?
I'm fine.
And Mum and Dad?
Better than me.
Strutting about affectedly, looking at each other now and then.
Tell me,
Is everything alright over there?
Everything's fine, so to speak.
Farah was asking for his photograph.
Hey!
She'd run an ad on TV,
'Missing person', get it?
With your voiceover.
Is she mad?
Tell her he's not missing!
She's lost him!
Alright --
Just give her a picture.
I know he's not missing, too.
May I request something?
Sure.
You better not call me.
I have no quarrel with you, but
It's only you or Afzal who calls me.
When you call, I get a feeling
That it's him...
A ray of hope shines bright when the phone rings,
But gets extinguished at the sight of your name.
Please,
Don't mind it.
You've got everything, right?
We've only got our Afzal.
We, his family, live in hopes of seeing his return.
Tell Farah, too -
If she started pitying people like this,
She take the Lord's affairs into her own hands.
There are many in Hyderabad who, embarrassed or vexed,
Have left their homes.
Why doesn't she worry for any of them?
The picture... It's not really about the ad...
Well, then, that's just --
Worse, innit, Lubna?
Remember,
She turned my brother down, pushed him away
Every single time!
We honoured her right to do so.
It's only fair that she, too, honour our right to refuse now.
I don't think she deserves so much as his picture now.
Yes, Dad?
Come and sit here.
So what have you figured?
Have you tried getting at what's gotten into her heart?
What is she thinking of and why?
Please send her to Karachi.
And if I didn't?
The decision is yours to make,
But please, just let her complete.
But why is she vouching for her?
Because I'm with her all the time,
And I know her better than you.
I also know
That your order will crumble before her will in but a few days.
So, it's better that you think about what she wants
Than getting angry with me.
What does she want?
The three of us must see...
Farah?
No, Dad, a psychiatrist.
You think I'm not the full shilling?
I would never go!
Why are you saying such things?
Just try to understand what I'm saying.
This girl will drive us mad.
That's right.
That's just what I'm saying --
Alright, I'll look for a good psychiatrist.
She must get treated, but will she go to him?
She'd say the moment she'd hear, 'You think I'm mad'?
Then, let her go to Karachi.
Not again!
She's stumbling around in the dark within herself.
She wants to prove
That she just sympathises with him.
Who?
Afzal.
However in the blazes is Afzal related to this?
How is he not?
Just -- She's denying it...
Care to explain in simpler terms?
Tell me.
Explain like I'm unlettered and nescient!
She loves Afzal...
I don't feel the slightest of sorrow on hearing this.
But it'll grieve you to hear
That she doesn't know this herself.
What?
Whatever the dickens is she talking about, Irsa?
She's french fried my brain!
I'll take my leave.
That's what I don't like one bit about you.
You immerse your father in simmering hot oil, fry him into a croquette,
And then say, 'I'll take my leave'!
Dad, she'll think we're conniving against her.
What else are we doing?
Fair enough...
I'm seeing a psychiatrist tomorrow morning.
I need a good psychiatrist!
Go.
Who shut the door to Dad's room?
Dad, of course.
Were you there?
I was coming back from there
When I saw you get out.
So you've heard everything!
Ration my rum if I understood anything except 'french fries'.
How do french fries fit in the serious conversation?
That's what I'm wondering.
Dad's lost his English, apparently.
He said, 'You've french fried my brain'!
Never heard that one before... 'French fried my brain'.
You don't get it.
You know how they slice potatoes to make chips?
Must be talking about that.
But why?
He said it when I said,
'Let Farah go to Karachi'.
It doesn't sound like something
That'd french fry his brain.
I also said,
'Even she doesn't know why she's going to Karachi'.
In other words,
You said,
'Farah's gone mad'?
I swear by God I didn't say that.
Seeing a psychiatrist doesn't mean you've gone mad.
Lubna?
-Just once.
At least it'll satisfy everyone.
Who will it satisfy except you?
I have no such issue.
But Dad's officially lost it.
He facepalms the moment he hears what you say.
All of this is because of you.
You're trying to prove to Dad that I'm certifiable,
And telling him
That Farah's not the full shilling!
Good Lord!
I'm sure you even said
That I'm going to Karachi to look for that runagate.
There!
You overheard the whole thing, didn't you?
So you actually said all of that!
Just in the flow of conversation... I said,
'Well, it's possible'...
Oh God...
But he didn't feel the slightest of sorrow to hear this.
It's rather surprising, Farah,
He's usually merry as a grig at the mention of Afzal!
Get out.
What?
I said get out!
If you poked your prating trap in my affairs again,
Or gave any bright ideas to Mum and Dad,
I'll kill you for real!
Hold it, Farah.
You're taking everyone except yourself lightly.
People other than yourself
Are not marionettes;
They have never, and will never dance to your tunes.
I'm your sister,
So I double as a psychiatrist when you need one.
But your 'madness' doesn't convince anyone!
Care to ask
What about Afzal's picture?
And what Arifa said when I asked her for one?
What did she say?
She said you don't even deserve his picture.
Tell me,
Do you?
No.
Not at all.
Let me give you a parting piece of advice.
Run an ad for yourself on TV,
'Missing person'.
With my voiceover,
Tearfully saying,
'This girl is searching for herself'.
'Please help her',
'Or pray for her'.
His build looks fit.
Could you have your hair cut?
Hair?
Why'd he need a haircut?
Babu, boyo, I want him to look like a commando!
But why --
-I'm talking to Babu Hamid.
He's been scoring third division marks throughout.
With his excellent credentials, he won't get a job inside the office.
Then?
He can get one outside.
Outside?
He can be a security guard.
His uprightness works in his favour.
He's the man for the job.
He'll earn 10,000.
Now and then,
He'd salute the toffs, open the door for them;
I'm sure they'll be glad to reward him.
I'm sure he'll make some 15,000.
Isn't it a tad too low?
How much do you want, sir?
1.5 million a day.
Stop laughing.
You may note it down.
One day, you'll be working as a security guard under me.
You have a fit build too.
Aye, I can see a bit of your belly, but...
It'll do.
Come, Babu Hamid.
By the way,
This is for the tea.
Keep the change. Consider it benefaction.
What was that about 1.5 million a day?
Are you thinking of becoming a politician?
Nothing else would earn you so much!
1.5 million a day, perhaps even 150 million a day.
I used to make aeroplanes like that in my younger days.
Tad would say in a lively voice, delighted, 'Mark my words, Arifa',
'My son will become a pilot one day'.
Arifa?
My Mam.
Hey!
My sister's name is Arifa!
Surely, your Mam's name isn't Ruqaiyya?
Yes!
My Mum's name is Ruqaiyya.
How do you know?
Ruqaiyya was my younger sister.
Wait...
'Was'?
She's gone now.
My Mam, my Tad,
My sister, my brother...
All gone.
Where?
They're dead, boyo.
Gone.
All at once?
Yes.
All at once,
One night,
One a minute earlier,
Another a minute later.
They had an accident?
No accident, mun... Murder.
Four murders for one-fourth an acre of land.
Acreage, boyo, has in its nature
A particular hunger for corpses.
Sometimes, when it's ravenous,
It may not settle for anything under eight.
Eight?
But you just said four.
Four of them died too.
I killed them.
Farah?
Please step aside.
Who is it, Arifa?
It's Farah, Mum.
Farah Ibrahim.
What's my son done this time?
My dear,
We are no longer responsible for his words and deeds.
He's left our place.
When you leave for another country,
It's their laws you live by.
I'm not here to talk about him, Aunt,
Nor do I have any complaint.
Right...
So you've just come...
To meet us.
In the Lord's name [auspicious beginning].
Have Farah sit.
Ask her if she'll have tea or coffee.
Tea or coffee?
Do I deserve coffee?
If I don't even deserve his picture,
How do I deserve to have coffee at his place?
Uh...
What brings you here?
What are you looking at down there?
He isn't here yet.
So what? Big deal.
Why are you worried so much about him?
I'm not worried about him.
I've been thinking about lunch.
If he didn't have lunch, he'd say when the month's over,
'No lunch, no money'!
Why wouldn't he?
We cooked the food for him, right?
Anyway, mind yourself when you lean.
It's a long way down.
He's here, Mam!
Serve him food.
That one seems to be his room.
Yes.
It is.
Why have you locked it?
Mum has a feeling he's in his room when it's not locked.
Oh...
He's done a BA, right?
Third division throughout?
What kind of job will he get with that?
I mean, he had a chance in Hyderabad, you know...
Quite a few bigwigs around here know Uncle, too.
Who'd want him in Karachi?
Mark my words,
He'll end up in bad company.
God will help him.
God will,
But only if he does something too.
He could've done an MA.
Maybe
He could've done better?
He's done with his studies, Farah.
Anyway... That's his personal matter.
But there's no wisdom in it.
I figure he must've left a letter?
Yes.
He has one for theatrics, I'd give him that!
What'd he say?
The letter is also his personal matter, innit?
Ah, yes...
Sorry...
Anyway,
He wrote,
'I'm not coming back until I've become something'.
But I wonder what...
I mean --
Surely, he must've thought of something?
He never got the opportunity to think.
He'd be thinking now.
Honestly,
You don't blame me, do you?
Uncle Reverend surely wouldn't,
But your Mum...
Perhaps she thinks he left because of me?
No --
Tell me...
It won't hurt me.
I, too, feel that it was my fault.
What's your fault?
When I'd --
Brought his letters
Before your Mum and Dad...
Why'd I have to say any of that?
I could've just called you
And said,
'I swear by God',
'I haven't written those letters'.
Yes.
You could have...
But you!
You barged into my house and created a scene!
I was furious!
Everything happens for the better, Farah.
Hollow sayings!
Nothing bad
Ever happens for the better.
What's so bad for you?
Wouldn't it hurt me?
I mean -- Your Mum and Dad --
My heart sinks to think of them.
I feel as if I've committed a grave sin.
You haven't sinned.
An honourable and virtuous girl should do just what you did.
Innit?
You shouldn't regret this either.
Afzal's my brother, but
He wasn't being fair on you.
It's certainly wracked our hearts with grief that he's left,
But so has the fact that he's two-timing a girl.
Who?
The one who writes him letters.
Ah, right!
The other Farah!
I forgot her entirely!
Find out, Arifa,
Who she is,
What she does, and where she lives.
It's no use.
Why?
She can help us bring Afzal back.
How will that poor lass help us?
Her own love is at stake.
She'd have Afzal's new number!
Right!
I'm sure he calls her!
No?
I don't think he does.
That's why she writes letters.
I'm sure he writes to her too?
I mean, at least replying to her?
Perhaps.
'Perhaps'?
Obviously, he replies; That's why she writes to him!
She isn't mad,
To just keep on writing herself.
The most bizarre things can happen in love
That would never happen in sensibility.
Look, now,
At how you, in your senses, said it,
'The road ahead is yours alone, Monsieur',
'I have no ties with you'.
It ended there.
Now, if someone's ready to sacrifice his life for you,
But you have no ties with him,
What does it matter to you if he
Goes to Karachi or the wops?
Right...
You're right there.
But --
-What's with this 'but'
If I'm right?
Just pray that he becomes something and comes back,
And tells us who it is that writes him letters,
What she does, where she lives;
I'm sure I can convince Mum and Dad.
'Convince'?
Simple.
I'll get them married, of course.
Yeah, right...
They should get married...
It's almost evening, Arifa.
I'll take my leave.
You'd come again, wouldn't you?
Sure, why not?
I'll come again, if the Lord wills.
Why are you laughing?
Your brother's left home and gone,
And you're giggling gleefully!
No, Mum,
I'm tearing up to think of that poor Farah.
Which one?
The one who just left,
Or the one who never came?
How does she come in?
She'd come in if she were ever there.
-What?
Who wrote the letters, if she were never there?
Look,
I'm very restless to begin with,
Please don't give me new fears.
Fear the one who just left.
Don't think about the one who was never here.
I dread her already.
She's come here twice,
And left us clobbered each time.
O God, have mercy.
Does this lad not work?
Who?
What's his name --?
Afzal?
Yes, Afzal.
I'm sure he does.
What's it to us, though?
Where does he get the money from?
Now,
He's paid the rent for four months.
And,
On top of that, he's paid 10,000 in advance for his food.
How's he paying for everything?
Enjoy your mangoes, Mam,
Don't worry about the trees. [Mind your own business]
Yeah,
But we better check they're mango trees alright.
Not gonna lie to you, though, he's good.
He's upright and doesn't look the wrong way.
He seems the mim and modest type.
He's just a tad lippy.
Well, so are you...
Ruffling everyone's feathers like you do!
If I'm not lippy, these men would eat me alive!
To add to it, I'm rather comely.
What? Ain't I?
But of course you are, Jasmine,
But please don't say it yourself!
Should I serve dinner?
Go.
But please don't start prattling.
Aren't you afraid?
The police will find you one day.
Have you ever thought what'd happen then?
What's the worst they can do?
Throw me in the quod,
Send me to the gallows?
That it? Let them, boyo.
Let the fifth die...
Oh?
So why are you in hiding?
Go and face them,
Tell them you're ready to die.
I'm not ready to die just yet.
I'm not afraid of dying,
But I want to live on.
There.
Go and open the door.
The Reaper has come knocking.
Get out of the way.
And don't stare like that.
You could try asking for food yourself sometime, Babu Hamid,
Or is it that you folks don't feel hungry at all?
Never had to come to that.
You're here
Whenever we feel a bit of hunger.
Potatoes and lentils again?
Where's the potatoes?
Are you blind or do they call okras potatoes in Hyderabad?
Keep it there.
Sure.
You better know your limits.
Don't think of me as une femme frêle.
For the likes of you, I can be a ferocious wildcat.
I claw the faces of the insolent!
Hmm...
Good that you mentioned it.
I'd been thinking you're a girl for 20 days.
By the way,
What do I do to make you leave?
What?
Will you leave if I meow you?
No way, that's --
A catca -- how you call a cat.
So,
What do you say to shoo one away?
Bleedin' dog!
C'mon, mate.
Have your dinner.
I'm starving.
That wasn't right, Afzal.
What?
The punishment for breaking a heart is worse than gibbeting.
Fear it.
Come.
I've seen you.
Who is it?
-Afzal.
What are you doing here?
I'd
Come to return the utensils.
You came through here?
Yes.
I think you don't know
But as per the rental agreement, you're not allowed to open this door.
Anyway,
We'll talk about it in the morning.
Listen.
It's not Babu Hamid's fault.
He went to bed right after dinner.
I --
Thought this door leads to your place, so...
I came here on the pretext of handing you the utensils.
Pretext?
No, it's --
Babu Hamid thinks
I've broken your heart.
I couldn't fall asleep.
We don't have sleeping pills --
I'm not asking for a pill...
I'm asking forgiveness...
That's neat.
You're a right emotional man.
Does this apology come from your heart,
Or are you just apologising to impress me?
Why would I impress you?
I know this one!
You lost your heart to a comely lady,
So acted rough at first,
Then impressed her with an apology.
It won't be so easy with me!
I've --
Just come to apologise.
Not to impress you...
Alright, then.
It's okay.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Translation: Aditya Misra © Prime TV