♪Who were those people♪
♪Who won their love?♪
♪When obsecrating for rosebuds♪
♪I was presented with a garland of thorns...♪
♪Who were those people♪
♪Who won their love?♪
No.
I won't Dad at your work's.
I mean, I --
Won't work at your Dad's.
Who has asked you to?
Work for us till December.
For you?
It's your chance to get proper rich!
The designation will leave you awestruck!
H -- How much?
As much as you want!
I mean as much as you can think of!
And
Designation?
We can decide your designation if you agree.
Where's your office?
We don't have an office.
What?
Lubna,
I don't want a poltroon for this job.
No --
I'm not a poltroon.
Then just say yes!
Why are you asking about our office?
It's all legal, isn't it?
No,
I mean I've promised Dad I won't do anything dodgy.
I'm sorry.
'Dodgy' just slipped out...
Then say it firmly that you're ready!
What's with the firmness?
I mean,
Does it involve a threat to my life?
It may.
So say it plainly that you won't do it.
How can that be?
I'll put my life on the line for it!
-Good.
That's the spirit!
What's the job?
I'll tell you. Have something first.
How will I have something?
I'm not hungry.
You're lying.
You were opening your lunch box before my eyes!
No --
That was because Arifa had said...
Actually,
Arifa orders me like a mother, so I thought I'd eat.
I wasn't really hungry.
Lubna,
Let's talk business.
Alright, how about 200,000 a month?
200,000?
Farah will pay from her personal account,
Which is why you aren't getting any more.
And we'll give you additional allowance
For your dresses and all.
You --
You're must be kidding!
You're kidding.
You're pretending as if you've never seen 200,000.
I haven't.
I've only seen the 98,000
That I won in the matches.
*Hem* 'Gambling'.
Can you stand firm and talk to our father?
I can.
But I have great respect for him.
He called me today and said, 'Take your place at our office'.
Are you out of your mind?
You'd leave a job that gets you 200,000 for one that earns you 10,000?
No...
But --
Must I stand firm before him?
Is he into this business too?
The entire business lies in his hands.
You just have to snatch it from him for four months.
What are you looking for?
A handkerchief.
Thank you.
It's sinful to snatch the business from a father's hands...
Listen to the whole thing.
Yes?
I'm all ears...
The thing is, Farah's getting married to Mehtab Chawla on the 15th of December.
Look at me!
Right, so where was I?
Glass -- water.
Did you hear what I just said?
Y -- Yes.
So, Farah doesn't want to marry him.
But now that the date's been fixed, the situation's got a bit hairy.
But Farah's found a way out.
She's mustered the courage to tell Dad
That she does not want to marry Mehtab
Because she loves someone else.
Which isn't quite true either.
She doesn't love anyone.
She just wants the marriage put on ice.
And
That's where you come in.
Come in?
Come in, as in, do this job.
What do I have to do?
Love Farah for four months --
-What's this balderdash!
I -- I mean, act as if you love her.
Stand firm before Dad, saying,
'I love Farah so much that I'd die without her'!
Take it quietly if he wants to whack you.
And, if he aims his gun, say resolutely,
'Shoot me'!
But I can assure you
It won't come to that.
And even if it did,
His aim's nawful!
My aunt made it out alive, too!
Excuse me...
Why did he black out like that?
I've told you,
He's taken a shock.
What shock?
I'm letting him love me for four months, and I'm paying him for it! 200,000!
How could this ever shock a clerk earning 10,000?
Try to understand, Farah.
It's troubling him right now.
Why?
Don't forget who he is.
I can't forget that.
I hope you'd understand, then,
That he thinks like the Reverend.
Meaning?
What does he think?
He's thinking
About what a girl from an honourable family is doing to one-up her father!
Put a sock in it!
It's barely days since he turned so faithful!
When one has newly turned faithful,
He sticks to his principles faithfully!
Anyway,
Don't worry.
We can find someone else.
What?
You want to besmirch my name everywhere!
That blighter will tell his sister.
What'll she think about me?
Nothing! She'll just call me
And ask me about it.
I'll just say
'He's lying'.
You'd better.
And say it in a way
That if the Reverend heard it, he'd break his face!
May I go now?
Where?
Sit.
And don't you dare budge from here until this smirch is washed off me!
Smirch?
Oh God...
Who is it?
Dad?
It's me.
It's you!
How come you're back so early?
-Let me get in.
Why are you shivering?
No idea...
Where's Mum?
She's gone to Aunt Kausar's to lustrate her child.
She'll be back soon.
Get me a quilt.
A quilt?
This cold is killing me...
Go to your room.
Take me, will you?
You have a fever too...
It's just a fever...
Seems like malaria.
No.
I don't have malaria.
I say
Go and see a doctor.
What do I tell him?
For God's sake,
Get yourself checked up.
Why are you feeling so cold in the summer?
Could it actually be malaria?
Just give me a quilt.
I'll start sweating in a moment.
You would, sure.
Okay, I'll get you one.
What do I have to do?
Love Farah for four months --
-What's this balderdash!
I -- I mean, act as if you love her.
Stand firm before Dad, saying,
'I love Farah so much that I'd die without her'!
Here.
Quickly, now...
I think you're fine!
Show me your hand.
The temperature's worn off...
Shall I turn on the fan?
-No blimming way!
What's with this rudeness?
Why'd you say that?
Just slipped out --
I mean, don't turn on the fan.
I'll start shivering again.
You've got malaria, then.
That's what makes you hot and cold.
Really...
It isn't malaria.
I swear.
Would you please tell me what happened?
Stay quiet, Mum!
Walk so that your footfalls cannot be heard!
Alright...
Come.
What happened?
-Malaria.
What?
It doesn't seem so...
Not me, Dad, he's got it. Afzal!
He's in his room wrapped in a quilt.
A quilt?
-Yes.
Came back early.
-Oh?
I swear, Dad, he was shivering so much!
Come and see!
Look at him.
He's all drenched with sweat.
Why didn't he see a doctor?
I asked him to,
But he didn't agree to.
What's this with 'agreeing' to it?
Wake him up.
Everything seems alright here...
Get up, young man!
Dad?
It's you...
What happened?
Nothing.
Arifa here
Told me you were shivering when you came back?
Back then, yes...
I'm fine now.
So you won't see a doctor?
What'd I do?
No shivering now... No fever too...
I hope everything's alright at the office?
No --
No problem there.
It's been two days since Monseigneur came for his morning prayers.
He doesn't usually do so when he's in town.
You see him around, don't you?
Some --
Sometimes, yes.
Alright, I say
You get some rest.
Prepare some yahni for him.
If he starts shivering again,
Drag him to the doctor's.
Call me later.
Yes, Dad.
And when will your mother be back?
Before sunset.
Alright.
Close the door.
Get me some yahni, will you?
And yes,
Where's the key to the cupboard?
If I'm not mistaken,
Monseigneur's daughter
Is your friend, isn't she?
What's her name --?
Lubna.
What happened?
Nothing, really.
I'm sure she calls you?
Yes, sometimes.
She always asks about you.
Meh.
Sit down for a while, so that I, too, get a feeling that I'm preparing yahni for someone who's ill.
Such ornate sets, Madame, that would bedazzle Farah!
Not a single bangle is without diamonds.
So you've bought everything?
Why not?
Bought them and had them kept in the locker.
We're now thinking about the dresses.
I'm looking at gold embroidery samples.
It'll take at least 50 biscuits.
Biscuits?
Bars of pure gold, you know.
We call them 'biscuits'.
Oh...
And Mehtab here said that he'd gift her a Ferrari on the wedding.
A Ferrari?
It's a bit dear, yes, but
Certainly not more than our Farah, is it?
Tell me,
What about your preparations?
We're just deciding...
Deciding?
Monseigneur will call you in the evening when he's back.
That's new.
New?
The men of your family talk about the wedding preparations?
He's
Been preparing for a few days.
He'll tell you everything today.
Okay.
I would request you, Madame...
Yes?
Ask Farah
To talk to Mehtab sometimes.
What's with all the shyness?
Why, it's only natural that --
I mean,
That'll be decided tonight too.
Right...
How could I say this to Monseigneur?
God willing, it won't come to that.
He'll tell you everything.
Alright,
I'll talk to him about this too.
Give my love to Farah.
Bye.
Ohh...
You agreed to everything she said.
Not so fast.
It's just a matter of a few hours.
It'll all get started
As soon as Monseigneur calls.
Hey!
You're out here, studying peacefully,
While they're deciding your future!
Tonight, at last, you'll have to tell
Who he is.
What can I do?
Think about it and tell me his name!
Who do I name?
You suggested that blighter,
But he blacked out as soon as he heard it!
Purify yourself.
Purify?
It isn't time for praying yet.
Time for voluntary prayers.
Resolve to offer 100 of them.
On your prayer mat, soldier, double time!
What are you saying?
Jeez, girl!
When you can't find a way out yourself, ask for God's help!
Quickly; Mum's coming.
And Dad's coming in an hour too.
Which prayer is she offering right now?
It's time for neither the sunset one, nor the dusk one.
Care to tell
Which prayer is she offering right now?
Voluntary prayers.
She'd vowed
To offer a hundred additional prayers if she got her wish.
A hundred?
What's her wish?
The one about Mehtab.
She's even taken to praying regularly that she's not married off to him.
She's offering additional prayers to fulfil her vow,
And Shugufta's had jewellery worth millions made.
And she told me that every kind of ornament
Has diamonds studded in it.
So how is this cause for worry?
They'll be of use to someone else.
When your father declines, yes...
If your father declines.
Why don't you just ask him?
'Please decline'!
Call that lad first.
She's not even telling me his name.
She'll tell you after her prayers.
Stop her halfway.
Tell her she hasn't got her wish yet.
She'll be complaining to God for nothing later on.
And tell her yourself
To be downstairs with all his details before your father arrives.
Otherwise, it's none of my responsibility.
Lord, no shame in falling in love with him,
But now she's feeling shame in naming him!
How many are you done with?
Just 12.
-Enough.
Ask for blessings, and get back at it after the news bulletin.
Why?
Ask for blessings,
Bolt the door,
Sit and think who he is!
Dad will be trying you in an hour!
Dad will call to decline
Only if you can argue your case before him.
Or else
Neither your destiny, nor the date of the wedding will change.
Where are you going?
Please keep me out of it!
Your narking's fried my brains!
You could say I'd die the moment Dad would thunder.
No more help, sweetheart.
It's over!
Oui, Monsieur Mehtab?
Not Mehtab...
Afzal.
Hey!
It's you!
I thought you'd never come to once you were out.
No.
I'm fine now.
Why did you call me?
To say yes.
Yes, as in?
The job and designation you were talking about...
I mean...
I'm in.
Really?
Would I call to lie?
You've thought about it, haven't you?
This job means putting your life on the line.
Dad can do anything when he's furious.
Please
Talk about Farah.
Farah?
Don't you remember
What she said at the restaurant?
What?
'It may involve a threat to your life'.
Yes?
Do you think your father will kill me?
Quite possible.
Alright, then.
Fine by me.
I will sacrifice myself.
But please tell me...
Yes?
This love will go on for four months?
You'll have to keep it going on.
Will we meet, too?
Obviously, you'll get to meet us.
But what after four months?
Do you know how much you'd earn in four months?
800,000.
That'd be enough.
Start a business with it and keep on blessing Farah.
The love ends there?
Love?
I mean -- the job...
The job ends the day Farah likes someone
And Dad says, 'He's the one'!
What about me?
What about you?
Dad will never agree on you.
By God, he'll create such a scene at the mention of your name --
Dad will create a scene, and the two of you will act your parts.
Farah will weep before Dad, naming you,
And you will fall at his feet, saying,
'Uncle, I can't live without Farah'.
'I'd die without her; I'd take poison'!
Then?
What, then?
Farah will threaten him similarly.
Her threat will scare him for sure.
Won't he agree if he got scared?
I mean -- for his daughter...
But don't worry,
We've thought of a way out of that too.
What's the way out of that?
You'd two-time Farah.
Two-time?
That's what everyone will think
First, love her with all your heart,
And then run away a two-timer!
What do you mean, 'Run away'?
Blimey --
Can't you understand what I'm saying?
What'd a two-timer do?
What?
Leave for Karachi for a few days, my good man...
Change your phone number,
Farah will weep before Dad and say,
'Afzal's left me, Dad'!
'He's smitten with another girl'!
I swear by God, there's no one!
Who's asking you?
By the way, is it your Oul Wan
Who writes you letters?
Anyway,
Just think
Your relationship ends
The moment you two-time her.
That's it.
That's what she wants you to do and that's what she's paying you 800,000 for.
Is it too little for you?
It's too much.
The perfidious deserves not a penny.
Alright, I'll get back.
Tell her the deal's done.
I'll do exactly as she says.
Farah!
If you're afraid that I may get angry on hearing his name,
You're mistaken.
It's okay if you love someone,
And I said
I'd reject Mehtab after meeting him.
Why are you getting worried?
Don't you think
I'm a liberal father?
I consider it natural to love,
As long as it does not smirch the girl's honour.
I --
I swear, Dad...
You don't need to swear.
I trust you.
Just tell me his name.
Give me his number.
I want to talk to him.
And I promise you that once I've talked to him, I'd call to decline Mehtab.
What's the problem with you now?
Say something; answer him!
Ease her a bit.
Even if he's a tad lower in status or rank,
Accept him.
All of that later, Irsa.
Let her say something.
Just a minute!
I'm sorry, Dad.
But if you give me a minute, she'll say everything.
Okay. Come and sit here.
Not here, Dad...
I'll take her along for a minute.
Okay.
Take her.
He's neither turned tail,
Nor declined.
He's agreed.
He's even agreed
To sacrifice himself
If Dad would rather have his head.
But today, you will only mention his name.
You will not say he's Reverend Subhanallah's son.
Did he say that?
I'm saying this.
Start off with the sparklers
Before igniting the bigger bombs.
But Mum will suspect immediately.
She'll ask, 'Are you talking about Reverend Subhanallah's son'?
What should I do, then?
You've been performing well enough so far,
Just keep at it.
Mention his name, and come out of the room demurely.
Mum would swoon.
Dad would swoon, too.
But you better remain in your senses.
Get up the moment you name him,
And before they come to,
Slip out sharpish.
What's the matter now?
Will he come if you call him?
Why should I call him?
You call him now.
He'll open up when you talk to him.
Open up, as in?
He'll have to open up so he can speak openly before Dad!
Haven't you seen
He starts stammering when talking to you!
Monseigneur says that it's been a minute.
Go
And tell him quickly
That his name's Afzal.
May we talk right now?
Yes.
What's his name?
I'll only tell you his name today.
Alright.
Just his name today.
Afzal.
Afzal isn't his name --
That was a remark about his character.
That's his name.
It wasn't a remark about his character.
May I go?
Who's this Afzal?
Reverend Subhanallah's son?
Is he the same?
Tell me!
Answer me!
Is it him?
Yes.
It's him...
How is it that you're swooning over a lad from the neighbourhood,
And I haven't the foggiest?
That means
I've failed in my duties as a mother.
I told you, Mum...
It was just childhood feelings.
I realised when we grew up
That I love him.
I don't meet him.
Don't leave this stone unturned!
The thing is
Given the time of a year or a half,
I can correct my mistake.
How will you correct your childhood love?
Uhh...
Didn't it ever occur to you,
The mention of his name could kill!
I made a mistake...
A mistake's committed once
And never repeated again.
Now, tell me what I should do...
That's why I -- wasn't telling you his name...
His name's more than we can handle!
Call him tomorrow.
And ask him to meet me first.
What'll you do?
Let Dad meet him...
You want that he should say something before your Dad
That overwhelms his heart.
Traditionally, it's the mother who meets the boy first.
Alright. Call him
And ask him when he's coming.
Also, tell me
What he likes to eat.
Leave it be, Mum.
Just -- serve him some tea.
As you wish.
A --
Ask Dad
To call Mehtab.
Don't worry; he will.
Now that you're determined, everything will end up in your favour.
May I go now?
My phone's upstairs in my room...
Go.
Done earwigging?
Shut up!
Translation: Aditya Misra © Prime TV