♪Who were those people♪
♪Who won their love?♪
♪When obsecrating for rosebuds♪
♪I was presented with a garland of thorns...♪
♪Who were those people♪
♪Who won their love?♪
Don't you feel ashamed to think
That she loves you, and she's looking
For the one you love?
Come.
Come on, mate.
You started down the path of God. Where'd you end up?
Nowhere.
You just left Hyderabad and ended up in Karachi.
And here you are, thinking whether
You've never left Hyderabad,
Or never returned from Karachi.
How are you, Mr Fiancé?
Come in.
I saw you playing cricket.
You're such an ace, mate!
Don't say 'mate;' Dad may hear it!
Allow me these parting discourtesies, my love;
Who knows what may become of me
Who knows what may become of me and you?
Tell him to not look at me with such fury!
Don't look at her with such fury!
Why did you go there?
Eh?
For the sake of Uncle Reverend's coconut biscuits.
Please agree to what I'm saying!
And for your Mum's sake.
She finds you in Farah.
And for your sake, M. Afzal,
For I see her in your eyes.
It occurred to me that you'd gotten engaged for my happiness;
For your happiness, then, I thought I'd break this engagement.
Uncle, ask him
To return my ring.
You're under my oath!
What are you saying?
Please, Jasmine.
Don't say such things...
I've made a promise to the Reverend,
And you're so one-sided -
You agree to everything the Coconut Girl says;
Won't you agree to one thing I said?
Dad's crying, Jasmine...
He loves you so much.
I love him so much too!
I, too, will tear up when I'll remember him.
C'mon!
Return my ring.
Mam was asking me on that day, 'What kind of engagement is this'?
'Which the boy's parents didn't attend'?
I said, 'Thank God he's here'.
'I would've agreed to the blighter's proposal had he asked to get engaged over the phone'.
♪Every compeer♪
♪Every compeer abandoned me♪
♪After ephemeral moments of companionship♪
♪Who has the leisure to stand by♪
♪One so crazed in love♪
I'm not returning your ring.
I'm keeping it to show it off before Mam!
I'll tell her it's a long term engagement,
And I'm waiting a lifetime for the marriage...
C'mon now.
Drop me at my place.
I'd written all those letters, Lubna...
What letters?
The same
That Afzal has.
A lie.
You're lying.
Don't say 'You're lying' now that I've accepted it.
I've been caught because of Miss Mary D'Souza.
I would never have admitted it.
And when you'd gone to Afzal's place after ritual purification,
And said to his mother that you can swear on the Qur'an,
Why did you say that?
You were ready to commit such a grave sin!
I knew she wouldn't let me.
Good Lord!
I'm so ashamed already...
Forgive me... Please...
Try to make a list
And see how many people you'll need to apologise to, and how many will forgive you.
Dad will punch you right in the jaw!
I'm determined now, Lubna...
I'll take it.
And when God asks you,
What will you do about that?
Jasmine's taken care of it,
She said, 'Confess the sins of lying and breaking him'.
'I'll weep for you and ask forgiveness for you'.
She was weeping?
A lot.
She loves Afzal so much...
One-sided.
And that blighter loves me.
So she sacrificed herself for you.
I'd tried to dissuade her,
I said,
'Marry him'.
You're so simple...
But she said, 'Be uncharitable in love'.
'Had I been in your place',
'I would've trampled everyone underfoot'!
You must've learnt that instantly,
Seeing how you trampled Jasmine underfoot in a moment!
I love Afzal, Lubna...
Tell me, then,
What do I do?
Call Sibtain,
Say to him, 'I'm not marrying you'.
Why don't you --?
Poor chap's a good man.
I guess I'll have to now...
Else, everyone's going to say,
'These girls just like to get things started',
'They never get things moving forward'.
It's my sacrifice for you!
Call her here.
Tell her her dresses are ready.
Tell her to have a look, get ready; we're leaving.
Where's Mum?
At the jeweller's; she told me to come with her.
She's selecting the jewellery?
Of course!
Come with me.
Get these upstairs.
D -- Dad...
Please endure this final bulletin --
Final bulletin?
Slap me if you get angry.
But say to Mum it's my decision.
I mean -- yours.
Don't say a word about Farah.
I don't want to hear any news about her.
I promise, Dad.
I won't say anything about Farah.
Have no fear, then.
Tell me - what is it?
Uh --
Dad -- It's --
You know -- Sibtain?
What happened to him?
Nothing!
Please listen patiently.
Alright, go on...
It's --
Dad, Sibtain was --
Actually for me.
I mean -- he --
The proposal --
Was intended for me.
What?
I swear, Dad.
But I said, 'There's one condition'.
What condition?
You're getting angry, aren't you?
Blimey, I'm not getting angry!
Get over with it.
The condition was that
He'd cure Farah completely.
Cure her?
What do you mean?
Dad, she's cured!
She's admitted that she used to write those letters to Afzal!
Nobody will mention Afzal in this house now!
Let me finish, Dad!
Isra will die if she heard anything like this!
She's in on it, Dad!
I've french fried your brain, haven't I, Dad?
But this time, the mistake wasn't Farah's.
I've fried it this time.
For God's sake, what will Sibtain's parents think?
Nothing at all!
They're in on it too!
Why did you have to conceal it from me, then?
You can't act, Dad!
We thought it'd be better if you performed naturally!
So she's 'cured'!
Completely, Dad!
Don't you all think it's a bit too late now?
Be honest with me -
Have I been more of a father to you or a friend?
A friend, of course.
Tell Farah, then, that no friend would ever advise her
To even think about Afzal.
You're saying this because of Jasmine, right?
She's no more --
I mean, she's breaking the engagement.
She's the one who explained everything to Farah.
She said that the engagement was just like Sibtain and Farah's 'marriage'.
Only that she'd been a tad bit serious.
But Afzal was just getting even.
Even -- as in, Farah got engaged the other day,
So he got envious and got engaged on the same day.
He's committed 12 murders in Karachi, Lubna.
He'll have to pay for them all.
She'll have him pay for it.
She'll ask him why he did it.
He must have an answer too.
Otherwise, he'll just say sorry --
Come on, Lubna...
Let me think like this, Dad...
He's back now.
He's playing cricket here in Hyderabad.
Let him play.
Don't talk about murder.
How far is Karachi, anyway?
Here you go and there you arrive!
Don't cry, Aunt.
We'll talk over the phone.
I'd never talk to you.
Tell me,
Who am I to talk to you?
You're family.
The one-sided engagement, remember?
Given that, you're my mother-in-law.
50-50.
Where's Uncle?
He'd be in his room, crying...
I thought I'd meet him.
It's me, Uncle... Jasmine.
May I come in?
Don't you dare set foot in the room!
I don't want to meet you!
Not at all!
Please allow me...
I'll be there in your heart even after I'm gone...
Every time you'd look at the Coconut Girl, you'll bless me.
Scold me if it's a lie.
Otherwise, let me go.
I have to,
Whether you grant me leave,
Or not.
God be with ye...
You're leaving because Farah used to write letters to me, right?
Let me tell you the truth...
She didn't write those letters to me.
I used to write those letters myself under her name.
No.
That's not why I'm going.
I'm going because
That blighter loves you.
So much that she cannot bring herself to say it.
She started crying buckets and buckets when she was about to say it.
Who is it?
Sibtain and his father.
Why are they here?
And why are they laughing?
They're happy
That Sibtain's not getting married to you.
Oh seriously!
As if I'd marry that ignoble psychiatrist!
What were you looking at over there?
Afzal was going somewhere with Jasmine.
Look at how she turned away!
She didn't even meet me as she left!
Don't be so happy about it.
She's left this place with tears in her eyes.
Bless her in your 12 prayers now that you're getting married to Afzal.
Did you talk to Afzal?
Not even now?
Ask him to talk to me.
You're both trapped in these issues.
He couldn't say it, and nor could you.
I'm never saying it.
Alright.
Wait until the marriage.
You'll come out with it all.
Where are you going?
Downstairs.
The date of your marriage is being decided.
Dad's saying you'll get married this Sunday and the next Sunday will mark the celebrations.
But -- Uncle Reverend didn't even talk about it...
The two of them don't have such issues as you two!
There was one Jasmine,
Who loved my brother,
But my brother
Loved Farah.
Seeing it, one would believe that if love is one sided, it becomes more than mere love,
but what does love turn into
When it becomes something
More than mere love?
It's midnight, isn't it?
Yes.
Why did you set an alarm for midnight?
I figured
He would've arrived by midnight.
He must've arrived there.
We're going to Monseigneur Ibrahim's tomorrow.
Are we invited?
What are you saying, Ruqaiyya Begum?
It's the girl's family.
Why would they invite us?
We'd go to them!
We'd beseech them humbly,
'Please'
'Be so generous'
'As enrapture us by giving us Farah'.
Jasmine?
Jasmine, wake up. We're at your place.
Thank you.
Listen.
Won't you ask me to come in?
No.
I'll start to grow on you if you come inside.
You'll forgive me, won't you?
Did you call Farah?
Call her.
Tell her how much you love her.
I'll forgive you that instant.
Take care.
Listen...
If you ever visit Karachi...
Do not pay me a visit.
Did you call Farah?
Call her.
Tell her how much you love her.
I'll forgive you that instant.
Dear Afzal,
Do you know the most undeniable truth in the world?
Don't guess.
Hear it from me:
The most undeniable truth in the world is that
Farah Ibrahim
Loves you.
Hello?
Afzal --
Yes, Afzal?
Go on; why did you stop?
Afzal?
Do you have the slightest shame?
Farah, let's go --
Hey! Get off!
Let me see who's the boss!
Now that your engagement plan failed,
You stand in my way to get even?
You're playing the lover in front of everyone?
Want to besmirch my reputation?
You're Reverend Subhanallah's son,
So I thought you wouldn't step out of the house for days after all the insult that day.
You'd drown in shame,
Or leave Hyderabad to hide your disgraceful self!
Hello?
Farah here.
I know --
The call got disconnected?
Yes --
Disconnected.
So what was it you were saying?
I was saying --
That's what you always do.
It's either that you can't say,
Or can't say the whole thing.
Go on.
I'm listening.
Farah,
Yes...
Say something after 'Farah' and you'll see
How everything just flows naturally!
Hello?
Tell me...
Why did you call me?
I wanted to talk to you about the letters.
Yes, go on?
Move on from the letters.
But, I --
Alright.
I'll start.
But -- You finish it.
I wrote all those letters.
For you.
To you.
A fib...
All the letters, I --
I wrote them myself.
To you...
Sorry --
Why are you saying sorry?
You were right.
So what if you'd written them?
Go on.
These long pauses of yours, Afzal,
Something's not right.
It's cost a lot before.
C'mon, be a man!
Tell me clearly that --
You love me.
That's it --
What's it?
I love you...
So much...
But Farah,
Don't say 'Farah' like that...
I might die when I hear it.
There you go again!
Listen,
I've written a letter to you.
For real this time.
I'll post it tomorrow, and you'll get it in a day.
Don't ask me what I've written,
Just...
Know that it opens with 'Dear Afzal'.
You're so shameless.
Said it to my face that you love me so much!
Now, I'm a girl;
I have to think.
I've written it after a lot of thinking.
I'm not telling you anything else.
You're on the way, aren't you?
When will you get back?
Tell me...?
Please tell me...
Hello..?
Please?
How many times to I have to tell you, Afzal,
Your silence costs all of us so much.
♪Who were those people♪
♪Who won their love?♪
♪When obsecrating for rosebuds♪
♪I was presented with a garland of thorns...♪
♪Who were♪
♪Those people♪
♪Who won their love?♪
♪When looking for the garth of happiness♪
♪The sands of sorrow engulfed me♪
♪When desired an ode to love♪
♪Cold sobs rewarded me♪
♪Every compeer I found doubled my heart's grief♪
Translation: Aditya Misra © Prime TV